<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" media="screen"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/~d/styles/rss2enclosuresfull.xsl" media="screen"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>American Planning Association</title>
        <link>http://media.planning.org/</link>
        <description>Welcome to the American Planning Association's Podcast directory. This is your source for discussions, lectures, and symposia on a multitude of planning topics. </description>
        <generator>Feeder 2.4.5(1806); Mac OS X Version 10.9.5 (Build 13F1911) http://reinventedsoftware.com/feeder/</generator>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>American Planning Association</copyright>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 11:37:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 11:37:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to the American Planning Association's Podcast directory. This is your source for discussions, lectures, and symposia on a multitude of planning topics.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:image href="http://media.planning.org/podcast/apa.jpg"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:owner>
            <itunes:name>Michael Johnson</itunes:name>
            <itunes:email>mjohnson@planning.org</itunes:email>
        </itunes:owner>
        <itunes:new-feed-url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/AmericanPlanningAssociation</itunes:new-feed-url>
        <itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
        <itunes:category text="Education"/>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: Eugenie Birch, FAICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Courtney Kashima, AICP, interviews Eugenie Birch, FAICP in this special World Town Planning Day edition of the "People Behind the Plans" podcast series.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 07:00:50 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-the-Plans-Eugenie-Birch.mp3" length="26754681" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">999EE20B-2FF0-4945-84CD-47C35B2A3AD9</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>27:48</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: Lynn Ross, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode of People Behind the Plans, Courtney Kashima, AICP talks with Lynn Ross, AICP, Founder of Spirit for Change Consulting. Lynn discusses how she discovered the field of urban planning, equity in the planning profession, her work with the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Knight Foundation, and much more.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 17:11:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-the-Plans-Lynn-Ross.mp3" length="40990785" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">75E2538C-C3D9-4166-B485-D97E7263513D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>42:37</itunes:duration>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/APA_647_sd_300.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: Bev Wilson, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode, Courtney Kashima, AICP, talks with Bev Wilson, AICP, Associate Professor at University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, Department of Urban and Regional Planning.  Their wide ranging conversation includes consideration of new frameworks for civic technology. They touch on how planners can think about extending the scope of tech tools to include planning issues such as equity, vulnerability, and the connection between rural and urban planning. Whether in virtual or in person space planners have the tools to lead the collaboration for the public good.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 16:36:48 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-the-Plans-Bev-Wilson.mp3" length="57373532" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2F170E64-3F11-40B9-B817-EC2F184F91A3</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>59:41</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Streets Health Impact Assessment</title>
            <description><![CDATA[The Green Streets program is an initiative in Lawrence, Massachusetts with a goal of increasing vital tree cover throughout the community. Through collaboration between Groundwork Lawrence, APA's Sustainable Communities Division, and the Massachusetts chapter of the American Planning Association, the Green Streets program was the focus of a detailed and comprehensive Health Impact Assessment or HIA. In this episode, Jennifer Henaghan, AICP, Deputy Research Director and Manager of APA's Green Communities Center, interviews Angela Vincent, AICP, Economic Development Planner with the Merrimack Valley Planning Commission, and member of APA's Sustainable Communities Division; Brad Buschur, Project Director with Groundwork Lawrence; and Neil Angus, AICP, CEP, Environmental Planner with Devons Enterprise Commission, and also a member of APA's Sutainable Communities Division.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Green-Streets-Health-Impact-Assessment.mp3" length="41271234" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1EB9DDC6-CC21-453A-A4EB-612EDCC8D360</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>42:55</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: Scott Page</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this episode, Courtney Kashima, AICP, talks with Scott Page, founder of Interface Studio in Philadelphia and a leader in developing unique and innovative urban design ideas. The pair discusses who’s driving the changes that are shaping cities, the influences of partnership, “unintended consequences,” and the inspiration that comes from the conversation around public works.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 16:14:28 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-The-Plans-Scott-Page.mp3" length="24748050" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8D2D1C4F-A1F6-4D3E-8342-72FB40531E69</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>25:42</itunes:duration>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/APA_647_sd_300.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: David Fields, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In the second episode of the People Behind the Plans series, Courtney Kashima, AICP, chats with David Fields, AICP, at the 2017 National Planning Conference in New York City. David is Principal at Nelson Nygaard in San Francisco and the former chair of APA's Transportation Division.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 15:14:13 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-the-Plans-David-Fields.mp3" length="24234386" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A1CE9809-804A-4969-B643-FE5A7A6F01C6</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>25:10</itunes:duration>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/APA_647_sd_300.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People Behind the Plans: Jamie Simone, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[This is the first episode in a new series that explores the business of planning for the built environment. Hosted by Courtney Kashima, AICP, planner and small business owner of Muse Community + Design in Chicago. Each episode features conversations between planners on work, life, ideas and problem solving in a variety of communities. In this episode Courtney has a conversation with Jamie Simone on her role with the plan for the innovative public space and alternative transportation corridor; the 606 in Chicago.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 16:21:41 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/People-Behind-The-Plans-Jamie-Simone.mp3" length="40599578" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0310D8DC-C4A2-4580-9810-B0E1421FB9D7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>42:13</itunes:duration>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/apa.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Disruptive Transportation Technologies: Interview with Andrew Salzberg from Uber</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA's Editor in Chief, Meghan Stromberg, interviews Andrew Salzberg, Head of Transportation Policy and Research at Uber. This interview is part of a series about disruptive technologies within the world of transportation featured in the April 2017 issue of Planning magazine.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 15:04:34 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Andrew-Salzberg-Uber.mp3" length="21550707" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">96557A82-F44B-49B0-B74B-04A5997116A5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>22:22</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Disruptive Transportation Technologies: Josh Westerhold from Nissan's Future Lab</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA's Editor in Chief, Meghan Stromberg, interviews Josh Westerhold, Senior Manager of Nissan's Future Lab. This interview is part of a series about disruptive technologies within the world of transportation featured in the April 2017 issue of Planning magazine.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 14:19:05 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Nissan-Future-Lab-Josh-Westerhold.mp3" length="31033758" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C1468EED-E373-4737-9235-018D11BACA4B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>32:15</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Disruptive Transportation Technologies: An Interview with Zagster's Jon Terbush</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA's Editor in Chief, Meghan Stromberg, interviews Jon Terbush, Communications Manager from bike share company, Zagster. This interview is part of a series about disruptive technologies within the world of transportation featured in the April 2017 issue of Planning magazine.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 16:53:41 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/zagster-jon-terbush.mp3" length="21485087" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2226EB5F-1608-4184-A3B4-4532385CE39D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>22:18</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Previewing APA's Infrastructure Principles</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Jason Jordan, APA's Director of Policy, interviews Kara Drane, AICP about APA's forthcoming set of principles that should guide a new federal infrastructure program.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 16:42:27 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/infrastructure-principles.mp3" length="8045154" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EB5668E0-DD54-46ED-AEEB-A243AF96C168</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>8:18</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Delaware Coalition for Healthy Eating and Active Living</title>
            <description><![CDATA[The Delaware Coalition for Healthy Eating and Active Living is working to include health and equity elements when updating comprehensive plans within the state. This podcast features an interview with David Edgell, AICP, Project Lead for Plan4Health for the Delaware Chapter of the American Planning Association, and Tim Gibbs, Executive Director Delaware Academy of Medicine and Delaware Public Health Association.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 16:57:55 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Delaware.mp3" length="18723201" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B769F05D-5912-4092-8D0B-436C26859E68</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>19:26</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Helena, Montana</title>
            <description><![CDATA[An interview with Karen Lane, Preventions Program Manager at Louis and Clark Public Health, about how the Healthy Communities Coalition is working to develop an active living wayfinding system for parks and along urban trails in the greater Helena, Montana area.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 16:46:11 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Helena-Montana.mp3" length="10441718" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7AE2FC7F-B564-4DAB-9A90-43E19838E616</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>10:48</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Pathways to Health in Tulsa County, Oklahoma</title>
            <description><![CDATA[An interview with Chad Call, Shared Use Specialist, and Luisa Krug, Chronic Disease Epidemiologist, both of the Tulsa Health Department on the Pathways to Health initiative.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 16:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Tulsa-County.mp3" length="14258528" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">68F307DA-364E-4EC0-85C6-392ECC9C9815</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>14:47</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Active Transportation Community of Interest - Pierce County, Washington</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Liz Kastor, The Active Transportation Community of Interest (AT COI) manager,  discusses how the organization, through the Plan4Health coalition, seeks to increase access to safe, healthy, and affordable active transportation options for people living in the Puyallup Watershed in Pierce County, Washington.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 15:13:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Pierce-County.mp3" length="11474526" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B702719A-6028-4DBF-8863-40754F15AD82</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>11:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Tarrant County, Texas</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Linda Fulmer, Executive Director of Healthy Tarrant County Colaboration, discusses how the Plan4Health coalition is helping to bring access to healthy food in the southeast Fort Worth area.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 10:35:50 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Tarrant-County.mp3" length="14396872" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9DB062EC-B3BE-48AF-969D-08CDFC6340CC</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>14:55</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planner Profile: Courtney Kashima, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this edition of Planner Profile, APA interviews Courtney Kashima, AICP, Principal at MUSE Community + Design and President of APA's Illinois Chapter.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 11:03:44 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Planner-Profile-Courtney-Kashima.mp3" length="12748446" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">90520482-7405-48B8-BDD9-183A187F56E4</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>13:12</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Umatilla County, Oregon</title>
            <description><![CDATA[A discussion about the work of the Plan4Health coalition in Umatilla County, Oregon with Jessica Nischik-Long, Executive Director at the Oregon Public Health Association, and Becky Steckler,AICP, Program and Policy Manager at the Oregon Chapter of the American Planning Association]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 13:19:03 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Umatilla-County-Oregon.mp3" length="18556404" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BBE49E19-3824-46D5-9280-E72726A2A47B</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>19:15</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Thomas County, Kansas</title>
            <description><![CDATA[A discussion about the work of the Plan4Health coalition in Thomas County, Kansas with Eldonna Chestnut, chair of APHA's Council of Affiliates, and Dr. Robert Moser, President-Elect of Kansas APHA.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 13:12:25 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Thomas-County-Kansas.mp3" length="22850096" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FA781E9F-C0A6-4E36-A78B-F85AE243C824</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>23:44</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Parks in Washington D.C.'s NoMa</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Washington D.C.'s NoMa neighborhood has seen a tremendous amount of rapid growth in the last decade and with no land set aside for parks and publicly accessible space. We learn how that challenge is being addressed in this podcast interview with Robin Eve Jasper, President of the NoMa Business Improvement District and President of the NoMa Parks Foundation. Robin is also joined by Stacie West, Director of Parks Projects for the NoMa Parks Foundation.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 14:50:06 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/NoMa-Parks.mp3" length="22212723" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C2E31393-2192-4010-A56C-F343CE901728</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>23:04</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Journey From Planning to Public Service: Interview with Jack Molenaar, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Jack Molenaar, AICP, a transportation planner with more than 22 years of experience in both the public and private sector, give his perspective on both areas of his career, as well as his experience attending a national presidential convention.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 15:04:52 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/jack-molenaar.mp3" length="7831592" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">28391325-87E1-4390-B96E-6543D6093B12</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>8:04</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planner Profiles: Miguel Vazquez, AICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA's Career Services Manager Bobbie Albrecht interviews Riverside, California planner, Miguel Vazquez, AICP on his planning career path, including advice for emerging planning professionals on how to move forward within the field.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 16:34:01 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Planner-Profile-Miguel-Vazquez.mp3" length="14423206" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">51633131-0660-4702-92FD-272929DF0099</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>14:57</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Finding Economic Value in Parks</title>
            <description><![CDATA[A discussion on the Economic Impact of Parks nationally, and how Arlington County's Park Commission is using a recent economic impact study to help make the case for Parks and Recreation in the area. Featured speakers include; Kevin A. Roth, Vice President of Research at the National Recreation and Park Association, Elizabeth Gearin, AICP, with the Arlington County Planning Commission, William Ross, vice chair of the Arlington County Park and Recreation Commission, and Jennifer Fioretti, deputy director at the Arlington County Department of Parks and Recreation.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 16:08:42 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-Finding-Economic-Value-in-Parks.mp3" length="52767211" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C8C0A5F7-49DD-4AFC-9220-571AA5D1776E</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Community Preference and Transportation Survey</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The discussion with Hugh Morris, AICP, LEED, manager of the Smart Growth Program for the National Association of Realtors focused on the results of the recent poll of residents in the 50 largest metropolitan areas in the U.S.</p>

<p>The poll focused on biking, walking, and transit use as well as the degree to which respondents would be willing to live in a smaller home if it meant they could walk to more places.</p>

<p>The large sample size, 3,000, provides an opportunity to examine the data though several demographic lenses.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 15:49:24 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-CommunityPreferenceTransportationSurvey.mp3" length="40896767" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ED728071-DBA3-4949-A2EA-DAAF22DD07FA</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>42:31</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beyond Mobility: Transportation's Role In Achieving Community Outcomes</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Mariia Zimmerman, Vice Chair of Regional Planning for APA's Regional and Intergovernmental Planning Division interviews Stephanie Gidigbi, Director of Strategic Initiatives at the U.S. Department of Transportation]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 15:22:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Beyond-Mobility-DOT-Gidigbi.mp3" length="44204075" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E2A1AD45-E72B-4A36-8671-EDA2FC7183CF</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>45:58</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Streetcar Returns to Kansas City</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Kyle Elliott, Division Manager from the Department of Long Range Planning & Preservation for Kansas City, and David Johnson, Vice Chair at the Kansas City Regional Transit Alliance, discuss the Kansas City streetcar project.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 09:04:51 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/KC-streetcar.mp3" length="25533396" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F9A69EF4-3648-4A60-A948-645CC2693E30</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>26:31</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Building Coastal Resilience Through Capital Improvements Planning</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Jim Schwab, AICP, APA's manager of the Hazards Planning Research Center interviews acting Director of NOAA's Office for Coastal Management and Chad Berginnis, Executive Director of the Association of State Floodplain Managers on the Regional Coastal Resilience program.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 16:32:31 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Coastal-Resilience-Capital-Improvements.mp3" length="37699381" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">13F56D51-1685-4C6B-83DE-01F01ACB59E6</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>39:12</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Dane County, Wisconsin</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Steve Steinhoff discusses Plan4Health and its role with the Capital Region Healthy Communities initiative in Dane County, Wisconsin.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 12:09:16 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Dane-County-Wisconsin.mp3" length="16515927" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">70005101-89E7-4425-8FB2-E7E1329BCEF7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>17:08</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Stormwater Infrastructure - 2015 AICP Symposium</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Recorded October 28, 2015 at the National Building Museum, Washington D.C.</p>

<p>In urban areas, stormwater presents major challenges for water quality. Runoff and combined sewer overflows result in impaired quality and degraded watersheds. Increasingly, green infrastructure approaches can treat and reduce discharge volumes and help mitigate flood risk, in addition to a range of environmental, social, and economic benefits. Learn from the experiences of Washington, D.C., and Philadelphia in adopting green stormwater management approaches.</p>

<p>Moderator
<br />David Rouse, AICP, American Planning Association</p>

<p>Speakers
<br />Paula Conolly, AICP
<br />Policy Strategist, Green City, Clean Waters Program, Philadelphia Water Department</p>

<p>Bethany Bezak, PE, LEED AP
<br />Green Infrastructure Manager, DC Water, DC Clean Rivers Project</p>

<p>Mathy Stanislaus
<br />Assistant Administrator for the Office of Solid Waste and Emergency Response, U.S. EPA</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 12:08:16 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/AICP-Symp-2015-GreenStormwaterInfra.mp3" length="133229623" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2F7EE6F5-18AB-45A5-8CA3-FA018B68B514</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>2:18:42</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Live Well Kingston (New York)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA New York Metro Chapter President, James Rausse, AICP, discusses the "Live Well Kingston" coalition in New York.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 12:01:01 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-LiveWellKingston.mp3" length="11945386" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">01F143BA-7FAE-4AB3-BA58-074BE2CDCBEB</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>12:25</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Why Local Food Matters</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Get an overview of what we know about changing consumer demand and some of the drivers behind these changes in demand. Learn how the USDA Agricultural Marketing Service's Local Food Research and Development Division is trying to help farmers and food marketers take advantage of the recent surge in local food demand through grant assistance, primary data collection, applied research on emerging business models, technical assistance, and market facility design.</p>

<p>Debra Tropp of the USDA outlines a recent effort to capture and quantify economic impacts of local food system investments. She discusses the rollout of a toolkit that can be used by planners and other development practitioners in responding to oft-repeated questions about the expected job creation and economic activity resulting from public investments in local food systems infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 10:55:18 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-WhyLocalFoodMatters.mp3" length="51947166" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0FB75CD7-301B-4C67-8749-5774C3560BA7</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:02</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Eastern Highlands Health District in Connecticut</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Small and rural planning and zoning commissions often have limited capacity. In response, the Eastern Highlands (Connecticut) Health District Community Health Action Response Team coalition will develop a toolkit aimed at assisting planning and zoning commissions with understanding how planning can impact long-term public health. In this podcast APA interviews coalition member Emily Hultquist about the project.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 13:11:32 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-EastHighlands-CT.mp3" length="8556720" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3860317A-48F9-4F93-8DF0-606706787A04</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>8:50</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Micro Placemaking with Macro Results: Designing DC's First Semi-Permanent Parklet</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In July, D.C.'s first seasonal parklet popped up along K Street's busy commercial district. Transforming two parking spots into a playful, interactive micro-park, it invites pedestrians and office workers into a small oasis with fern and liatris.</p>

<p>Called "parKIT," this new public space was designed by Gensler in collaboration with the Golden Triangle BID, as a toolkit for D.C.'s parklets. Wedge-shaped, multi-use modules of various heights can be scattered and rearranged by the public, and the scene at the parklet has been ever-changing since its opening.</p>

<p>In this presentation, the parKIT team discussed the lessons learned from the design process, various reactions, and discoveries through the daily operation of the parklet. Also, they shared their observations on how temporary urban spaces can generate a new type of participation and placemaking in D.C.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 12:14:16 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Micro-Placemaking-Parklet-Gensler.mp3" length="47350911" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CC440DB6-236F-4142-AF68-D5166BC36103</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>49:15</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Great Public Spaces: The Santa Fe Railyard</title>
            <description><![CDATA[The Santa Fe Railyard in Santa Fe, New Mexico was designated as a 2015 "Great Place in America" for the public space category by the American Planning Association. In this podcast Brian Drypolcher and Greg Hiner from the Trust for Public Land discuss how the Santa Fe Railyard became a vibrant public space.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 15:35:20 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/SantaFeRailyard.mp3" length="27358609" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">452E6928-3398-40AD-9CDA-1B5D1BAB9DFA</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>28:25</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Disaster Recovery Planning in Maui</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Jim Schwab, AICP interviews James Buika from the Department of Planning for the County of Maui and Tara Owens from the University of Hawaii Sea Grant program about disaster recovery planning in Hawaii.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 16:40:40 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Disaster-Recovery-Planning-Maui.mp3" length="22571317" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CD76C2D9-1F1E-4B74-8AB3-1C4548A89681</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>23:26</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: Encouraging Healthy Lifestyles in Boise</title>
            <description><![CDATA[An interview with Daren Fluke, AICP about the Idaho Plan4Health coalition.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 10:01:04 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Encouraging-healthy-lifestyles-in-Boise.mp3" length="8434285" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1EDED148-187E-4338-9F0D-87964DE96B00</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>8:43</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Plan4Health: B-Well Bensenville</title>
            <description><![CDATA[An interview with APA member and Bensenville, Illinois planner Victoria Benham about the "B-Well Bensenville" campaign which is part of APA's Plan4Health initiative.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 09:29:44 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Plan4Health-Be-Well-Bensenville.mp3" length="7026578" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BBCD1FA4-1065-4165-96FA-0D18263DC021</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>7:15</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>KVMR Roundtable: Drought and Planning</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Roundtable discussion on water shortage and drought originally aired July 13, 2015 on KVMR Radio in Nevada City, California. Discussion participants include Frank Meecham, San Luis Obispo Board Supervisor from District 1; Tom Tedd, Director of the Office of the Columbia River - Department of Ecology for the State of Washington; Vic Ferrara, Nevada County Office of Emergency Services; Jim Schwab, AICP, APA's Manager of the Hazards Planning Center.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 15:38:28 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/KVMR-Roundtable-Drought-Planning.mp3" length="58510377" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">12555BB4-CEFF-44CB-9206-AEA3F716F70C</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:00:52</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Source Water Protection in the 21st Century</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday, July 14, 2015</p>

<p>As news arises of drought, harmful algal blooms, and chemical spills across the nation, we are regularly reminded of the need to protect drinking water in our cities and communities. Every day, land use decisions affect future drinking water supplies, either intentionally or inadvertently. By protecting sources of drinking water through regular planning activities and practices like green infrastructure, we can build resilient, healthy, and beautiful communities.</p>

<p>The Source Water Collaborative formed in 2006 with the goal to combine the strengths and tools of a diverse set of member organizations to act now, and protect sources of drinking water for generations to come. As a member of the collaborative, APA works with partners like the Association of State Drinking Water Administrators, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, the U.S. Forest Service, Smart Growth America, and many others to help communities across the nation protect sources of drinking water.</p>

<p>Rachel Carlson is an environmental protection specialist in the Drinking Water Protection Division, Office of GroundWater and Drinking Water, U.S. EPA. She assists with geospatial analysis and outreach in a variety of projects to protect sources of drinkingwater and participates in the Source Water Collaborative, a group of 26 national organizations including APA that are dedicated to protectingsource water.</p>

<p>Jim Taft is executive director of the Association of State Drinking Water Administrators, which supports the efforts of drinking water program administrators in states, territories, the District of Columbia, and the Navajo Nation as they implement the provisions of the Safe Drinking Water Act.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 13:41:24 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-WaterProtection.mp3" length="49615810" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D12204ED-27EE-449F-AB9D-AA2C366526C6</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>51:36</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dutch Dialogues: An Interview with Dale Morris and David Waggonner</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA talks to Dale Morris, Senior Economist at the Royal Netherlands Embassy in Washington, DC and David Waggonner, president of Waggonner and Ball Architects in New Orleans about the "Dutch Dialogues" workshops.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:55:25 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Dutch-Dialogues-Morris-Waggonner.mp3" length="17830856" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C1C46808-53D1-476F-84E4-E34E451AEDEE</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>37:00</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Norfolk and 100 Resilient Cities</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 23:51:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Norfolk-100-Resilient-Cities.mp3" length="23456553" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E0119417-7CFF-42EA-86E6-33A5BDD1C794</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesday at APA DC: Linking Communities Together Through Innovative Regional Transportation Planning</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Linking Communities Together Through Innovative Regional Transportation Planning
<br />May 12, 2015</p>

<p>Metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) and regional planning councils are in the midst of a wave of innovative practices in how they work with communities to create long-range plans and how they work with local jurisdictions to implement land use, transportation and development decisions that support regional outcomes.</p>

<p>Mariia Zimmerman shared highlights of recent work that she has conducted through her company, MZ Strategies, looking at some of the emerging best practices including highlights from the Innovative MPO Guidebook published by Transportation for America. Specifically, what types of local assistance programs are being created to foster more livable communities, how are regional agencies incorporating social equity into their investment decisions, and what role are MPOs and regional planning agencies playing in cross sector regional collaboratives.</p>

<p>Erich Zimmermann focused on how MPOs and regional planners are innovating to provide better value to the communities they serve. Regional planners across the country are finding new ways to demonstrate their important role in transportation, economic development, and community well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 16:24:50 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-InnovativeRegionalTransit.mp3" length="52565388" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E8A6B529-144E-4DB7-A9EB-FF85E8C7087E</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:41</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Housing Equity and Healthy Housing Choices - 2014 AICP Symposium</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>2014 AICP Symposium - Originally Recorded on October 29, 2014 at the National Building Museum</p>

<p>"Housing Equity and Healthy Housing Choices"</p>

<p>Featuring: </p>

<p>Carol Payne, Director, Baltimore Field Office of the U. S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</p>

<p>Derek Hyra, Associate Professor, Department of Public Administration and Policy, American University</p>

<p>Jonathan Wilson, Deputy Director, National Center for Healthy Housing</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 14:43:56 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/AICP-Symposium-2014.mp3" length="145301300" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8A650BAF-97E6-4632-BAEB-66081D04EBA6</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>2:31:17</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Living With Water in the Big Easy: NOLA's Ride to Resilience</title>
            <description><![CDATA[On this episode, APA’s Emily Pasi talks with APA member Brad Klamer of the Sewerage and Water Board of New Orleans about the actions the City of New Orleans is taking to create a more water resilient, green and educated community. We’ll explore what cities New Orleans is looking to as models in resiliency planning and how the City is learning to live with water.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 09:40:30 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/BradKlamer-NOLA.mp3" length="13502105" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84DECD45-89A5-4487-9484-4D633FCCF488</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>14:01</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Strengthening Local Capacity for Data-Driven Decision Making</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>February 24, 2015</p>

<p>This talk drew upon lessons from the National Neighborhood Indicators Partnership (NNIP), a collaboration of the Urban Institute and organizations in 35 cities. NNIP partners help local actors use neighborhood data to improve communities through policy, planning, and advocacy.</p>

<p>From her experience in NNIP, Kathryn Pettit of the Urban Institute discussed the types of information infrastructure needed to make good decisions in a local community — including open government data, integrated data systems, community indicators, and neighborhood data systems.</p>

<p>Examples from local partners demonstrated how stakeholders are using local data on health, housing, and education to set priorities and make better decisions, including examples from the Washington and Baltimore areas. For more information about NNIP, visit www.neighborhoodindicators.org.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 15:26:08 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-DC-DataDrivenDecision.mp3" length="57354342" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F006AA64-2CB8-4803-80DD-83C537D96069</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>59:40</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Lighting Municipal Broadband</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA interviews Rodger Lentz, AICP, Chief Planning and Development Officer for the City of Wilson, North Carolina and Will Aycock, General Manager of Wilson's Greenlight Community Broadband. They discuss the city's recent successful petition with the FCC and how the issue of municipal broadband will continue to be important for planners.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 23:34:07 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Green-Lighting-Municipal-Broadband.mp3" length="16298237" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2BAE597F-00A7-49A9-A30B-7CD753CA2F39</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>16:54</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Chicago's Historic Pullman</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Pete Pointner, FAICP, former board member of the Historic Pullman Foundation in Chicago discusses the history of the Pullman neighborhood and its recent proclamation as a National Monument by President Barack Obama.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 10:36:01 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Chicago_Pullman_Pointner.mp3" length="24990039" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">04FABAF8-713E-42EA-852E-F082D8790DA2</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>25:57</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Supporting TOD in Metro Chicago</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday, November 18, 2014</p>

<p>Transit-oriented development (TOD) is defined by the Regional Transportation Authority (RTA) of Northeastern Illinois as moderate to high-density, mixed-use communities generally located within a half-mile radius (10-minute walk) of a rail or bus station designed to maximize walkability and transit access. Interest in TOD is driven by its ability to reduce traffic congestion; changing demographics; and a desire to live in mixed-use, sustainable, and walkable communities accessible to transit. </p>

<p>In this program, Heather Tabbert, AICP, and Tony Manno, both from the RTA, discuss how the Community Planning program has transformed over the years in response to the needs of communities, the results of a recent survey of TOD residents, and case studies of several diverse communities from throughout the region that have taken TOD planning from vision to reality.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 14:44:42 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-TODChicago.mp3" length="57210117" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">100B881C-5873-498A-9B4D-4AC71D9660E6</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>59:31</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: SymbioCity and the Planning of Hammarby Sjöstad</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Climate risks and sustainable growth are shared responsibilities — engineers, architects, planners, and developers are uniquely placed to improve the built environment. Sustainable development can both reduce emissions and cities' vulnerability to climate change and many impacts can be avoided, reduced, or delayed. Cities have the right density, economic conditions, and geographic scale for efficient public transport; recycling of water, waste, and materials; and energy production, distribution, and use. However, few cities have reached their full potential in these areas. There are major benefits with creating cities with substantial efficient use of resources, where transportation and use of infrastructure is both effective and attractive, land is used optimally, and the impacts on water and the natural environment are limited.</p>

<p>Cooperation and synergies require more coordinated solutions, as well as new construction with better environmental performance and more energy efficient transport vehicles. In this program, Stellan Fryxell from Tengbom architects, and Erik Freudenthal, from GlashusEtt, presented an overview of SymbioCity, the Swedish approach to fostering sustainable urban systems and processes. And they used the Hammarby Sjöstad waterfront redevelopment project in Stockholm, Sweden, to illustrate how the SymbioCity approach has been applied at the district scale.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 22:57:52 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-SymbioCity.mp3" length="64971180" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F03D2886-3BA4-4ABE-9006-EEA87128BF6E</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:07:36</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Private Capital, Public Good - The Daniel Burnham Forum on Big Ideas</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Private Capital, Public Good
<br />September 28, 2014
<br />National Building Museum
<br />Washington, D.C. </p>

<p>Featuring Guest Speaker Congressman John Delaney and a panel discussion with Ben Hecht, CEO of Living Cities, John Rahaim, Planning Director of the City and County of San Francisco, and William Anderson, FAICP, President of the American Planning Association</p>

<p>Today's fiscal and political realities make private and philanthropic investments ever more important to building communities. New tools like social impact bonds are rapidly moving from concept to reality. In Washington, Congress is debating how to leverage private and nonprofit involvement in infrastructure and housing. The latest Burnham Forum will zero in on these issues from the perspectives of the investors and communities working with new partners.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 14:31:45 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/PrivateCapitalPublicGood-Burnham.mp3" length="81216458" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">31B665A0-D543-47C1-90F3-A0F4D8DDFF9A</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:24:31</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Principles to Guide the Future of Planning Practice</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>September 23, 2014</p>

<p>The Chicago Metropolitan Agency for Planning (CMAP) projects a population increase of 1.96 million people and 1.24 million jobs in the Northeastern Illinois region by the year 2030. And the cumulative impact of planning decisions throughout the region will determine the degree to which the built environment will satisfy the broad objectives of (1) meeting human needs efficiently; (2) creating economically viable and sustainable communities; (3) shaping the built environment in harmony with the landscape and the natural and cultural environments that frame the context of a specific project or area; and (4) nourishing the human spirit by creating beauty, diversity, order, justice, and opportunity.</p>

<p>In this program, Pete Pointner, FAICP, presented seven key principles to guide the future of planning practice. Drawing on his book Planning Connections, Pointner emphasized the cumulative effects of principle-based planning decisions, focusing on the important role that planners play in supporting people, the environment, and our economic well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 15:54:16 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-PrinciplesPlanningPractice.mp3" length="52369334" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A6C7244A-F017-4876-821A-9F0E1E9370C5</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:29</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: "Wetrofitting" Urban Neighborhoods</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>August 26, 2014</p>

<p>Until recently, climate change has correlated to polar bears and melting ice caps — heart rending, but safely distant. Yet climate-related extreme weather, combined with urban development, is starting to show its force, as realized by the severe droughts in California and the misery caused to millions of home owners and businesses as a result of urban flooding. With these impacts comes the potential for public mobilization and a renewed focus on the way we plan our towns and cities. But can we channel individual concerns over wet basements and leaky pipes into a broader public participation and advocacy movement?</p>

<p>This July, the Center for Neighborhood Technology (CNT) launched Rain Ready (rainready.org), aimed at building an alliance of individuals and communities working together to find solutions to the problems of too much or too little water. Rain Ready is inspired by the growing number of resident actions groups in the Chicago region mobilizing as a result of the impacts of flooding in their area. It seeks to offer a response to their question: "What should we do?" In 2013, CNT launched Wetrofit — the nation's first service for property owners affected by urban flooding, and in 2014, CNT designed and promoted the Urban Flooding Awareness Act, which was passed unanimously by the Illinois General Assembly and requires the State of Illinois to carry out a study on the solutions to urban flooding.</p>

<p>In this program, Harriet Festing of CNT presented an overview of her organization's water-related work and discussed opportunities and challenges for planners as they engage their communities around the topic of urban water management.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 13:04:51 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-wetrofitting.mp3" length="55085661" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B054BE0B-3344-41A0-B8B3-95D5FD814617</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>57:18</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Front-Line Perspectives from APA's Community Planning Assistance Teams</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>July 22, 2014</p>

<p>APA's Community Planning Assistance Team (CPAT) initiative provides pro-bono planning assistance to communities with a demonstrated need and a lack of planning resources and expertise. Each CPAT pairs a multidisciplinary team of expert planning professionals from around the country with community members, key stakeholders, and relevant decision makers to foster community education, engagement, and empowerment.</p>

<p>In this program, Rich Roths, AICP, and Douglas Martin, AICP, shared insights from their respective CPAT experiences and demystifyed the process for potential participants. In September 2013, Roths led a CPAT looking at the potential future of a gateway commercial corridor located in a floodplain in Franklin, Tennessee. The previous year, Martin lent his expertise to a CPAT for Wakulla Gardens, a small-lot subdivision in otherwise rural Wakulla County, Florida. After summarizing these projects, Roths and Martin highlighted lessons learned for future CPATs.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 21:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-FrontlinesCPAT.mp3" length="59656889" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DE1C3552-B181-48DB-8B3C-35C8BBC6A95F</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:02:03</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA - Walkability: Fact or Myth?</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>June 17, 2014</p>

<p>Many contemporary conversations about sustainable design and development emphasize walkability. But, in terms of the potential effects of walkability on carbon emissions, it's important to separate fact from fiction. While there is no argument that walking contributes to health, pedestrian-friendly districts and neighborhoods may not be enough to significantly reduce vehicle miles traveled (VMT).</p>

<p>In this program, Lane Kendig, from Kendig Keast Collaborative, explored how the concept of walkability relates to four types of trips: commuting, shopping, recreation, and child-related. He discussed the connections between density, intensity, transit, and significant reductions in VMT. Through a series of case studies, Kendig made a case for the necessity of zoning reforms that prohibit auto-oriented urban development.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 20:58:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-WalkabilityFactorMyth.mp3" length="55924052" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6E4197EE-D163-437B-B5EC-C6625D59F64A</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>58:10</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: A Factory in Every Home? New Manufacturing Technologies and Metropolitan Spatial Development</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>May 20, 2014</p>

<p>Emerging manufacturing technologies, such as 3-D printing, promise to revolutionize the way things are made. Will they also revolutionize the spatial pattern of metropolitan development? Could these technologies lead to a radical decentralization of manufacturing through the proliferation of artisan-type shops within the next decade?</p>

<p>In this program, Howard Wial, from the University of Illinois at Chicago, uses concepts from economic geography to assess the ways in which emerging manufacturing technologies are and aren't likely to reshape the physical form of U.S. metropolitan areas and the location of manufacturers within them. He discusses how these technologies have the potential to create new opportunities for small and medium-sized manufacturers and the most likely locations for new manufacturers. Finally, Wial highlights some of the freight transportation and workforce development issues related to increased adoption of emerging manufacturing technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 16:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-Factoryineveryhome.mp3" length="58968532" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53C90E1A-35BD-4F69-ABF1-7EB09637BA18</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:21</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Parking Management Strategies to Support Livable Communities</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>April 22, 2014</p>

<p>As one of the largest single land uses in our municipal "footprints," parking deserves more attention than is typically bestowed upon it. Besides encouraging auto use, having an excessive supply of parking influences the character, form, function and flow of our communities. It makes walking and bicycling unpleasant and unsafe, it adds to flooding and pollution problems, and it makes housing more expensive. At the same time, parking is necessary to support a community's local businesses; finding the right balance between supply and demand — as an economist would — is the next step.</p>

<p>In the Chicago area, the Chicago Metropolitan Agency for Planning (CMAP) has been working with several communities through its Local Technical Assistance program to understand the unique parking challenges and identify potential solutions.</p>

<p>In this program Lindsay Bayley, from CMAP, discussed parking management strategies and presented the findings from two very different projects: downtown suburban Hinsdale, Illinois, and the Chicago neighborhood of Wicker Park/Bucktown.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 19:00:46 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-ParkingManagement.mp3" length="61140634" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B163EB49-F1D1-4FA1-BE2F-376E9FE3BB3C</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:03:37</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA - Municipal Design Review in Metropolitan Chicago</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>March 18, 2014</p>

<p>Both theorists and practitioners see design standards as shaping the "look" of the community and built environment over the long run — with significant underlying ideology. Planning professionals may view design guidelines and review processes as useful tools to communicate local preferences and resolve issues. And, design standards and form-based codes have become powerful branding and placemaking tools for suburbs in the Chicago metropolitan area and nationwide.</p>

<p>This program and discussion served to highlight contrasting perspectives on the benefits of design review.  Drawing on observations from public architectural review commission hearings in local suburbs, Professor Robert Rotenberg, from DePaul University, considered case studies of how design standards work to shape the development decisions by stakeholders in Cook County, Illinois. Attorney and consultant John Hedrick summarized the regulatory background and recent developments in the Chicago metropolitan area regarding best practices in utilizing design guidelines.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 11:30:56 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-DesignReviewChicago.mp3" length="55283370" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DF01F06C-A38A-496D-97EB-B818349BE1B7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>57:31</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA D.C. - The Missing Metric with Peter Katz</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Missing Metric</p>

<p>March 4, 2014</p>

<p>With the multiple crises of municipal insolvency, climate change and citizen pushback against government regulation at all levels, it makes sense to consider a new "balance-sheet" approach to granting development approvals. Such an approach would screen for more compact, high-value development that would pay back government's up-front infrastructure investments on a more rapid basis.</p>

<p>On first blush, the regulatory strategy would not seem compatible with Smart Growth and New Urbanism, both of which are strongly driven by urban design and physical form. Such models, which have gained wide acceptance among planners as preferred models for more sustainable community development, have proved difficult to implement within the regulatory structures that prevail in the United States and Canada.</p>

<p>By incorporating the "missing metric" into development review, municipalities may be able to reduce and even eliminate many cumbersome and highly subjective development regulations, and at the same time make it easier to achieve more amenable, resource-efficient and economically stable communities. For a recent article by speaker Peter Katz on the approach, visit 
<br />www.gfoa.org/downloads/GFOAGFRAug13MissingMetric.pdf</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 14:35:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-MissingMetric.mp3" length="69170864" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">717B0BDE-D555-4765-A2FB-0EB0FEB60063</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:11:59</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Case for the Calumet National Heritage Area</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>February 25, 2014 </p>

<p>The Calumet Region of Indiana and Illinois at the southern end of Lake Michigan has great ecological significance, cultural diversity, and economic might but is now grappling with questions of regional direction in the wake of widespread deindustrialization.</p>

<p>The idea of designating the Calumet as a National Heritage Area grew from a 1998 feasibility study by the National Park Service.The Calumet Heritage Partnership, formed as a result of the study, has worked to keep the Heritage Area idea alive.</p>

<p>Drs. Mark Bouman, from the Field Museum, and William Peterman, professor emeritus at Chicago State University, introduce the concept of National Heritage Areas with examples of successful NHAs in other parts of the country; discuss why NHAs should be of interest to planners; and show how the creation of a Calumet NHA would be consistent with and augment existing and evolving plans for the Calumet region.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 21:33:09 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-CalumetHeritageArea.mp3" length="59221380" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CBB45F5E-1226-46EE-8665-389053374900</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:37</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA - A Tale of Two Neighborhoods: The HUD Choice Neighborhoods Initiative in Action</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>January 28, 2014</p>

<p>The HUD Choice Neighborhoods Initiative employs a comprehensive approach to neighborhood transformation through the revitalization of distressed public housing and the creation of economic, social, physical, and educational initiatives. Through this initiative, planners and community groups are working to turn distressed housing and long neglected neighborhoods into viable and sustainable mixed-income communities that support positive outcomes for families.</p>

<p>In this program, Adam Rosa, AICP, of Camiros compared and contrasted planning efforts in two different Choice Neighborhoods. He shared the strategies that are being employed in the troubled Ellis Heights neighborhood of Rockford, Illinois, to foster positive neighborhood change through the arts and online entrepreneurship (including a strategic relationship with Etsy.com). In addition, he discussed the creative techniques being used to address the distinct challenge of gentrification in the rapidly changing Rosewood community of Austin, Texas.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 15:12:10 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-HUDChoiceNeighborhoods.mp3" length="56614581" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CE7DFE40-091D-41B5-AD05-A1C02A140AA8</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>58:54</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning Chicago: An Interview with Authors Jon DeVries, AICP and D. Bradford Hunt</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Authors Jon B. DeVries and D. Bradford Hunt discuss the state of planning in the Chicago region and their book Planning Chicago.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 14:06:55 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/PlanningChicago.mp3" length="20630403" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">378E5C4D-1652-434B-B27F-C33C7642A76E</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>21:27</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA DC - Innovation in Sustainable Urban Housing: Four Case Studies in Latin America</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>January 7, 2014</p>

<p>For the past three years, APA has been working in Latin America to promote urban planning. The most recent grant from the U.S. Department of State's Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas has focused on four innovative housing and community development demonstration projects in Bolivia, Brazil, Mexico, and Peru.</p>

<p>This presentation explains the background of the region's planning issues and showcases the progress of the four projects.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 11:47:26 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-ECPAHousing.mp3" length="59511046" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">34BD0D97-9F81-4C35-B2F0-9FFDCDBB2D32</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:55</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>People and Places: AICP Symposium 2013</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Immigration is woven into American history. But what about its future? Each year APA's professional institute, the American Institute of Certified Planners, hosts a fall symposium on a timely topic in planning. As federal legislators debate immigration reform, this fall's symposium looks at how immigrants affect the economies and cultures of the cities where they live and work. Hear regional perspectives on a dynamic group of people and their role in places across the United States. Recorded on October 29, 2013 at the National Building Museum in Washington D.C.</p>

<p>Panelists
<br />Stacy Anne Harwood
<br />Associate Professor of Urban and Regional Planning 
<br />University of Illinois, Champaign-Urbana</p>

<p>Fatima Shama
<br />Commissioner 
<br />New York City Mayor's Office of Immigrant Affairs</p>

<p>Leslie Wollack
<br />Program Director of Infrastructure
<br />National League of Cities</p>

<p>Paul Farmer, FAICP, moderator
<br />CEO
<br />American Planning Association</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 09:56:53 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/PeopleandPlaces-AICPSymposium2013.mp3" length="141188154" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">579C3A87-C2DC-423C-A414-CD83DD486C47</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>2:27:00</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA DC - Complete Streets: Closing the Gap between Policy and Practice</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>November 12, 2013</p>

<p>Across the country, hundreds of communities have embraced Complete Streets policies as a way to foster safer streets that serve everyone, not just drivers. But individual projects and general policies aren't enough: transportation agencies often struggle to reform decades of rules, practice, and politics that prioritize cars.</p>

<p>Barbara McCann, founding director of the National Complete Streets Coalition, has dug into what it takes to upend the way every transportation project is conceived, planned, and evaluated so each provides for people walking, bicycling, or taking the bus. McCann will discuss what she learned about why Complete Streets too often fail and what can be done to close that gap between policy and practice. She will share the stories of practitioners in cities and towns from Charlotte, North Carolina, to Colorado Springs, Colorado, who have made four fundamental changes in the way transportation projects are chosen, planned, and built.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 09:48:33 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-CompleteStreets.mp3" length="52457553" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3A982E95-520B-44BE-85DA-587E9956394F</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:34</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Plants, Paddles, and People - Creating Community through Green Infrastructure and Riverfront Development in Blue Island, Illinois</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>November 19, 2013</p>

<p>A growing number of cities across the country have begun to acknowledge their waterfronts as valuable community assets through plans, capital investments, and development regulations. The Cal-Sag Channel and Little Calumet River wind through the ecologically rich, but economically challenged Calumet region in Chicago's south suburbs. The region has received attention lately through the state's Millennium Reserve initiative, a new land bank and transit-oriented development fund, and possible national park designation for the Pullman neighborhood, and it's poised to take advantage of its rich water assets.</p>

<p>At the center of much of this activity is the City of Blue Island, Illinois, an inner-ring suburb straddling both banks of the Cal-Sag Channel. Jason Berry, from the City of Blue Island, and Abby Crisostomo, from the Metropolitan Planning Council, discussed a number of water-oriented planning activities happening in Blue Island — from neighborhood-based approaches to green infrastructure and stormwater management, to community engagement in the creation of a waterfront plan, to regional-scale planning for an intercollegiate rowing center and more. They highlighted the lessons learned for integrating the recognition of water as an asset into community planning.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 22:23:23 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-BlueIsland.mp3" length="59483093" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">17D8779D-E9FA-4144-BD64-DB751382231B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA DC: Planning the Home Front - How the Lessons of World War II Apply to Today</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>October 22, 2013</p>

<p>The American mobilization for World War II is famed for its industrial production; less well known is that it was also one of the greatest urban planning challenges that the United States has ever faced. Although Americans tend to think of World War II as a time of national unity, mobilization had a fractious side. Interest groups competed for federal attention, frequent — sometimes violent — protests interrupted mobilization plans, and seemingly local urban planning controversies could blow up into investigations by the U.S. Senate.</p>

<p>Drawing on her recently released book, Planning the Home Front: Building Bombers and Communities at Willow Run, Sarah Jo Peterson shows how the federal government used a participatory planning approach to mobilize the home front. For the massive Willow Run Bomber Plant, built in a rural area 25 miles west of Detroit, bringing the plant to success required dealing with housing, transportation, and communities for its tens of thousands of workers. It involved Americans from all walks of life: federal officials, industrialists, labor leaders, social activists, small business owners, civic leaders, and — just as significantly — the industrial workers and their families.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 14:13:47 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-PlanningTheHomefront.mp3" length="52552037" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A2F735CC-2698-47A3-A4D2-F4CAFE004373</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:40</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Speculative City</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>October 22, 2013</p>

<p>Despite the planning profession's origins in visionary thinking about the future of our cities, many contemporary planning practitioners are mired in the political battles of today and, therefore, can feel disconnected from the idea of imagining how the cities of tomorrow may have different needs and functions than the cities of today.</p>

<p>According to architect and urban designer Marshall Brown, from the Illinois Institute of Technology, future cities will be rooted in but not beholden to current realities. The cities of the future will likely be "mash-ups," recombining and repurposing infrastructure and design features.</p>

<p>Brown discussed his recent projects, including proposals for reimaging Chicago's Circle Center, and shared ideas about American cities and their futures.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 15:27:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-TheSpeculativeCity.mp3" length="59406915" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">379354A2-AD11-4EBB-A1F0-2D74046D8DCA</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:48</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Prioritizing Water Supply Planning in the Chicago Region</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday, September 24, 2013</p>

<p>While the greater Chicago region has historically had access to ample fresh water, it can no longer assume that water supplies are infinite. Without coordinated planning and policy, the Chicago region may be in jeopardy of forfeiting future growth and prosperity.</p>

<p>Fortunately, a lot has happened since the 2010 release of Water 2050: Northeastern Illinois Water Supply/Demand Plan that bodes well for water supply planning and management in northeastern Illinois, including the creation of the Northwest Water Planning Alliance, momentum toward a modernized state plumbing code, and the creation of the Clean Water Initiative. At the same time, there remains a lot of work to, including developing a sustainable revenue stream to support ongoing regional water supply planning.</p>

<p>Josh Ellis, from the Metropolitan Planning Council, will summarize the current state of water supply planning in the Chicago region, and highlight opportunities for moving Northeastern Illinois toward a more sustainable water supply paradigm.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 14:06:01 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-ChicagoWaterSupply.mp3" length="56114687" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6BEA4C69-8F82-43FB-AF6C-E2A0C199DE27</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>58:23</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: How Well Do Comprehensive Plans Promote Public Health?</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday, August 27, 2013</p>

<p>Since 2010, the American Planning Association (APA) has worked with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to examine the inclusion of public health goals within comprehensive plans and their implementation.</p>

<p>This presentation will identify best practices for the effective integration of public health goals into plans and successful approaches to cross-sector collaboration and community partnerships to implement those goals.  </p>

<p>Anna Ricklin and Nick Kushner of APA's Planning and Community Health Research Center offer case study examples of how local government agencies can build upon partnerships for assistance and resources to translate a comprehensive plan from policy document into a set of actions to improve community health. As built environment factors increasingly determine public health outcomes, this presentation offers a clear and targeted avenue for intervention at the highest level of built environment planning.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 14:25:46 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-CompPublicHealth.mp3" length="50616850" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7818D0D3-7508-4EC9-AE2F-50BBF02233F7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>52:39</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Emotions and Planning</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday, August 27, 2013</p>

<p>The more planners engage in collaborative participation the more they should expect to find people making judgments about the future tied to current emotional attachments. How do planners anticipate this and prepare activities and plans that encourage and foster emotional shifts?</p>

<p>Most planners and plans provide argument and evidence to inform clients about future changes giving reasons in support of different alternative responses. But these do not work in the face of emotional attachments to familiar and popular practices. The use of narrative and storytelling offers a way for professionals to anticipate and counter client attachments. Professor Charles Hoch, from the University of Illinois at Chicago, shared some highlights from his research about the effects of emotions on planning processes and discussed the power of narrative in planning.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 14:22:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-EmotionsAndPlanning.mp3" length="59681933" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0F6DA81C-171A-4D3B-AD72-996856AD0B57</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:02:06</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Walter Reed Reuse Plan as an Urban Design Case Study</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Walter Reed Army Medical Center Reuse Plan provides the urban framework for 66.5 acres of land to be transferred to the District of Columbia following closing of the military installation. The planning effort was led by the District Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development and the Office of Planning. This land has valuable frontage to 16th Street and Georgia Avenue, two major axial corridors, with the former originating in the White House and the latter being a major passageway between D.C. and Silver Spring.</p>

<p>Presenters Susana Arissó, AICP, and Martine Combal, AICP, discussed the cutting edge sustainable framework. This future neighborhood is set to become one of the five EcoDistricts in the Washington area, consisting of an exciting mixed-use development balancing new construction with historic buildings, open recreational spaces, destination retail, and residential, institutional and office uses totaling three million gross square feet. Located in an area of Georgia Avenue in dire need of revitalization, this plan envisions a "one-stop shop" for ordinary and extraordinary needs alike.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 11:36:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-WalterReedReusePlan.mp3" length="57019578" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CC3DF408-BA50-46A1-9EDF-AF4A3638968A</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>59:19</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Sex, Guns, and God! The 1st and 2nd Amendments and Local Regulation</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Constitution guarantees freedom of expression, freedom of religion, and the right to bear arms. Nevertheless, land uses that are dependent on these guarantees continue to court controversy in many communities. Whether sparked by chronic concerns over threats to community character or more acute debates related to public safety, many planners find themselves on the front lines of battles over contentious uses that have some claim on being constitutionally protected.</p>

<p>Drawing from practice-based experience and lessons from case law, Adam Simon and Dan Bolin from Ancel, Glink discussed local regulatory issues related to strip clubs, churches, guns shops and other land uses entangled with rights flowing from the First and Second Amendments of the U.S. Constitution.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 12:54:40 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-SexGunsGod.mp3" length="79852973" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">786C55A2-6683-4DC1-ABD7-96065291A994</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:06:29</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Purple Line Coalition in Suburban Maryland - Why TOD Is Not Enough</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Transit oriented development has become the holy grail of land use and transportation planners. The logic of concentrating both residential and commercial growth at transit stations — especially rail transit stations — is compelling and has ample empirical support. There is also evidence that transit accessibility increases property values near stations and that mixed use, high density development near stations increases transit ridership.</p>

<p>But investments in transit are designed to move riders through a transit corridor, thus the success of transit investments should be measured at the corridor, not the station, level. In this presentation, Professor Gerrit Knaap, director of the National Center for Smart Growth at the University of Maryland, introduced the newly formed Purple Line Corridor Coalition.</p>

<p>The goal of the coalition is to assure that investments in the purple line transit corridor achieve more than transit oriented development but serve as a stimulus for sustainable and equitable economic development throughout the corridor without displacing affordable housing or small businesses.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 15:43:26 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-PurpleLineMaryland.mp3" length="59975819" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">65CDF69F-F9A1-4F1B-B1EB-82653E20EB39</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Making Your Development Approval Process an Economic Development Tool</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>June 25, 2013</p>

<p>As we emerge from the Great Recession, communities with a predictable development review and approval process have a powerful competitive advantage in attracting private investment and economic development. Now, more than ever, limited access to capital, weaker markets, and less ability (or willingness) to share financial incentives is steering good development toward "easier" environments. "Winning" communities are delivering a predictable entitlement process that advances the community's planning and development objectives and rewards good development with less stress and less delay.</p>

<p>This concept is not about giving away the store, "padding" anybody's bottom line, or accepting undesirable development. The focus is on a balance between the assurance that communities must have from an approval and the predictability a developer seeks in navigating that process. Michael Blue, FAICP, from Teska Associates will draw on his experience managing municipal development departments and serving clients as a consultant to outline how communities can evaluate their approval systems with an eye toward securing desirable outcomes. The session will focus on questions such as: What parts of the approval process are most essential? What elements may be missing from your process that can provide greater confidence to city and developer?</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 14:49:25 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-EconomicDevelopment.mp3" length="57825836" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9BF7870D-2B2D-4430-AD9B-96B4BE40700B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:00:10</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Planning Chicago (Reviving a Place for Planning in the City)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Despite a storied planning history, Chicago is no longer a city that plans with confidence and vision.  Chicago lacks a city department with the name "planning" in its title.  Instead, this essential municipal function is now largely focused on immediate zoning matters with long range and strategic planning in a secondary role and largely replaced with piecemeal, ad hoc, and volunteer planning efforts – often funded and focused on disconnected Tax Increment Financing (TIF) districts.</p>

<p>The city had great success in the 1950s and 1960s in crafting strong central area plans and path-breaking comprehensive plans that laid the groundwork for a major commercial and residential revival. In the most recent decade however major planning initiatives have been largely unimplemented and replaced by deal-making, site-specific and one-off projects. Systematic, coordinated, long-range efforts have been difficult to initiate or sustain. Drawing on their new APA Planners Press book Planning Chicago, authors Jon B. DeVries, AICP, and D. Bradford Hunt of Roosevelt University will explain the rise and retreat of planning over the past half century and the need for a planning renaissance in Chicago.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 16:01:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-PlanningChicago.mp3" length="65090794" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BD53B868-9DEF-4082-B441-91AC3CA2E2BB</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Community Development Banking: What Your Bank Could Do to Support You</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The film It's a Wonderful Life grows more relevant every day as more American consumers lose the value in their homes and anonymous customer service calling centers become our primary contact with our banks. However, there are still more than 7,000 banks and 7,000 credit unions in the United States. Each of these still has the ability to convert your insured deposit into a loan to a local business and to step up as a community civic leader. Just under 100 of those banks are certified by the U.S. Treasury as "community development banks" and another 500 nonprofit community loan funds finance housing rehab, small businesses, and nonprofit facilities.</p>

<p>Ron Grzywinski and Mary Houghton will discuss the role that ShoreBank played as the first and largest community development bank and the increasing importance of community development financial institutions as long term partners in community and economic development. They will touch on the new Global Alliance for Banking on Values as well as opportunities for planners to contribute to more liveable, renewed communities.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 19:00:53 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-CommunityDevelopmentBanking.mp3" length="65122529" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">90FA33C2-64C3-458F-AD6A-7CFA0AF21DC5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Just Green Enough - Contesting Environmental Gentrification</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>While sustainability and green urbanism have become buzzwords in urban policy circles, too little analysis has focused on who gets to decide what green looks like. Many visions of the green city seem to have room only for park space, waterfront cafes, and luxury LEED-certified buildings, prompting concern that there is no place in the "sustainable" city for industrial uses and the working class. While it is difficult to find anyone against "sustainability," the process through which urban environments are being remade under the rubric of sustainability are highly contested. A major concern is environmental gentrification, in which environmental improvements result in the displacement of working class residents.</p>

<p>While social justice is supposed to be an explicit part of any definition of sustainability, the surge in environmental awareness in cities has not been matched with concern for social equity. Instead, the environmental dimension tends to obscure the social processes that created it. And yet, sustainable development can potentially provide communities with alternative ways of thinking about economic development, resource use, and social justice.</p>

<p>Drawing on case studies from both New York and Chicago, Winifred Curran from DePaul University discussed a strategy she calls "just green enough" to allow for an urban sustainability that can be used to open up a space for diversity and democracy in the neoliberal city and make space for interventions that challenge the presumed inevitability of gentrification.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:22:03 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-JustGreenEnough.mp3" length="58408837" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">213AB4C7-ECDF-4434-A838-A64814D19B2B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Supporting Conservation as a Land Use</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Conservation has often been considered a non-use of land, what is left over when other human needs have been accommodated. More recently, the importance of conservation as an intentional land use has been recognized for its role in supporting a variety of human needs: cultural, recreational, and ecosystem services with significant socioeconomic benefits. However, conservation is different because the factors that make an area valuable for conservation are not nearly as flexible and transportable as other land uses that can use a variety of technologies to make sites suitable to accommodate nearly any type of development.</p>

<p>NatureServe, an international conservation nonprofit organization, supports assessment and planning for conservation land use through a variety of products and services. The NatureServe Network of state natural heritage programs collect and provide data on the location of rare and imperiled species and ecosystems as well as expertise in the conservation of biodiversity. </p>

<p>In this presentation we will highlight these data and tools with some examples from around the U.S. to illustrate how they can inform better land use planning.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 19:00:36 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPADC-ConservationLandUse.mp3" length="57552044" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">242C1163-9EE9-488D-ACCC-36FBDA36A4BB</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Bus Rapid Transit in Chicago</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In Chicago, 1.8 million trips are taken by transit per day, and more than half of these are by bus. However, because Chicago's congestion is the third worst in the country, buses are often caught in traffic, making them slower and less reliable than they should be. There have been many studies looking at new rail options, including a downtown circulator streetcar and the Circle Line L train, but all have stalled because of the time and money needed to plan and implement.</p>

<p>For the last five years, the Chicago Transit Authority and the Chicago Department of Transportation have been planning Bus Rapid Transit in the city. The first new type of transit service since trolley bus service opened in 1930, the Jeffery Jump, is paving the way for Bus Rapid Transit in the Loop and along Western and Ashland Avenues. Christopher Ziemann, Chicago's BRT Project Manager, will discuss the unique approach that Chicago is using to advance BRT economically, politically, and technically.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 19:00:20 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-BRT-Chicago.mp3" length="54387651" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C83AFA99-688E-4888-A6DC-7E6A27852489</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Infrastructure Too Big to Fail: Interview with Professor Thomas O’Rourke</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Professor Thomas O’Rourke, Thomas R. Briggs Professor of Engineering at Cornell University, spoke in July 2012 at the Natural Hazards Workshop in Broomfield, Colorado, on the subject of “Infrastructure Too Big to Fail.”</p>

<p>Jim Schwab, AICP, manager of the APA Hazards Planning Research Center, caught up with him later to explore that subject in the context of natural disasters. Their conversation is the focus of this podcast.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 11:11:51 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/orourke-schwab.mp3" length="10241589" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">69ACDAE6-D7C6-45B5-8007-30E91CB64A98</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Great Recession, Municipal Budgets, and Land Development </title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>According to annual surveys by the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC) and the National League of Cities (NLC), cities have been eliminating jobs, decreasing infrastructure investments, and scaling back services for more than a decade. For many municipalities, the Great Recession has exacerbated these trends, endangering these communities ability to invest in future economic growth. Furthermore, the changing nature of municipal revenue structures affects land-use policy and the nature of future development projects.</p>

<p>In April 2012 UIC and NLC received a $950,000 grant from the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation to conduct a three-year study of municipal responses to the Great Recession. Michael Pagano from UIC shared some highlights of his research to date with a special emphasis on the immediate, and likely lasting, effects of the Great Recession on municipal revenue structures and decision making regarding the type, timing, and location of new development.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 19:00:44 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-GreatRecession.mp3" length="60435595" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8E99A906-5D3A-402C-A747-5C873F4BE39F</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association </itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Aging in Place: Planning's Role and Responsibilities (AICP Symposium 2012)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[As large populations in the United States are aging, our communities must adapt to this demographic shift. More people are living longer in varying locations from cities and towns to rural areas of the country. Planners are in a position to ensure that this growing population has access to services no matter what the context. Issues of mobility, food access, and healthy living are just some topics to be explored in this symposium. Panelists include: Sandy Markwood, CEO National Association of Area Agencies on Aging; Jana Lynott, AICP, Strategic Policy Advisor, AARP; David Ferleger, David Ferleger Law Office; and Elinor Ginzler, moderator, Senior Director, Cahnmann Center for Supportive Services, Jewish Council for the Aging.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 11:02:41 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/AICP_Symposium_2012.mp3" length="138808736" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F1CABF9D-CF8B-4DDE-89A2-DBC62767D7D8</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Complete Streets: Tools to Move from Idea to Practice </title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Streets are very often a community's largest public asset, yet they have rarely been described as such. In an era of higher gas prices, increasing rates of chronic disease, and an increased call for fiscally responsible investments, people are demanding another look at our streets. They want safe streets that provide a choice of travel modes and access to destinations near and far. They want complete streets.</p>

<p>An ideal complete streets policy is an inter-disciplinary vision and an actionable tool to create robust, safe transportation networks within and between our communities. But what are the real barriers to complete design? What do people really mean when they ask for complete streets? And why do so many projects result in incomplete streets?</p>

<p>Stefanie Seskin from the Complete Streets Coalition and Paul Lippens, AICP, from the Active Transportation Alliance will describe the 10 elements of a complete streets policy, and how that written direction can prompt transportation decisions that are responsive to community needs. They will also look at common themes encountered in Complete Streets implementation and offer 10 roadway designfixes for complete results.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 19:00:11 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-CompleteStreets.mp3" length="58257581" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">46CE8DAE-0FB9-4EA5-9F8E-E9DFEABB86C5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Greenest Building</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Each year in the U.S., approximately 1.7 billion square feet of buildings are demolished and approximately 5 billion square feet of newly constructed buildings are added to the total building stock. Until recently, the environmental impacts of this cycle of demolition and new construction have been poorly understood, as were the opportunities to gain carbon savings through building retrofit and reuse.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, the National Trust for Historic Preservation released "The Greenest Building: Quantifying the Environmental Value of Building Reuse," the most comprehensive analysis to date comparing the environmental impacts of new construction compared to retrofit and reuse of existing buildings. Commissioned by Preservation Green Lab, a project of the National Trust for Historic Preservation, the study found that building reuse typically offers greater environmental savings than demolition and new construction and that building reuse and retrofits substantially reduce climate change impacts.</p>

<p>Patrice Frey from the National Trust for Historic Preservation provided an overview of the study's findings and discussed how the study's data and methodology can be applied to the work of planning professionals.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 19:00:52 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-TheGreenestBuilding.mp3" length="58982916" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">A7EB8110-F98B-44F3-946C-B76FE4A8D5B2</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/apa_647_sd_300.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Bloomingdale Trail and Park Framework Plan</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Stretching 2.7 miles through four vibrant Chicago northwest side neighborhoods, the unused Bloomingdale elevated rail corridor is adjacent to numerous private properties and crosses over major arterials, a historic boulevard, bus and bicycle routes, and the CTA Blue Line. The conversion of this corridor into a trail and park will provide unprecedented connections to and among these communities.</p>

<p>The recently released Bloomingdale Trail and Park Framework Plan represents a critical juncture in the development of the project. Balanced between the efforts of the past and the development of the future, it strives to capture and harness the momentum and history of the project while defining a vision for the Bloomingdale's initial development and long-term stewardship. Beth White from the Trust for Public Land and Kathleen Dickhut from the City of Chicago will provide an overview of the collaborative planning process and discuss the plan's guidelines to design, implement, and manage a local trail and park with global appeal in the heart of Chicago's neighborhoods.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 19:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-Bloomingdale.mp3" length="81357003" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">16528480-B88C-4A93-A1E3-41A2EED29BA2</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA Chicago - Chicago's Food Plan: A Recipe for Healthy Places</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Obesity is the foremost public health crisis in Chicago and across the nation. More than half of Chicago adults and one-third of youth are overweight or obese, meaning they are at increased risk for serious, costly health problems such as heart disease and diabetes. A key focus in the city's obesity prevention effort is improving access to healthy food.</p>

<p>To this end the City of Chicago is developing a new food plan through a partnership that includes the Departments of Housing and Economic Development, Public Health, Family and Support Services, the Consortium to Lower Obesity in Chicago Children (CLOCC), and many stakeholders that include individuals and organizations representing health and food related issues. Bradley Roback from the City of Chicago will discuss the process of developing the plan and highlight strategies that seek to increase the production and distribution of healthy food, improve access to healthier food, build demand and increase consumption of healthy food, and capitalize on opportunities for job creation and economic development.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 16:11:04 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-HealthyFoodChi1.mp3" length="79805278" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4CFD0F73-5CA9-4A10-940E-7486EF09B947</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>In Motion: The Experience of Travel - An Interview with Author Tony Hiss</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Author Tony Hiss (Experience of Place), talks with Bob Yaro, president of the Regional Plan Association about his new paperback edition of In Motion: The Experience of Travel. Hiss and Yaro discuss how planners can take on the role of stewards of Deep Travel.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 14:45:27 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/In_Motion_TonyHiss.mp3" length="41330152" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">472187AC-065A-435C-9798-8FFE0B79154C</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA Chicago: The Legacy of Planning in Mariemont, Ohio and Riverside, Illinois</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Riverside, Illinois, and Mariemont, Ohio, are two acclaimed examples of early planned communities. Riverside's plan was created in 1869 by Frederick Law Olmsted, the designer of New York City's Central Park, and John Nolen developed the town plan for Mariemont in 1921 as a national exemplar. Both of these pioneer planners were landscape architects who understood that good planning is good business.   </p>

<p>In recognition of their uniqueness and significance, Riverside and Mariemont enjoy a special honor — designation as National Historic Landmarks. In addition, they possess such enviable but often elusive attributes as sense of place, strong community identity, and outstanding quality of life.</p>

<p>After presenting an overview of Olmsted, Nolen, and the two communities, former Mariemont Preservation Foundation president Frank Raeon, AICP, explained why the design principles used in Riverside and Mariemont merit not only further consideration but potential incorporation into the development patterns and character of communities.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 13:43:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesAPA-Riverside1.mp3" length="73392242" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">642C3493-F583-4E72-9E12-4F02DB8E596E</guid>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA Chicago - Closing the Gap: Public/Private Financing Tools and Development Feasibility</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tax increment financing (TIF) has always been a key tool in the municipal arsenal to make high-quality development projects possible. Since the recession and real estate crash, TIF and other innovative public/private financing mechanisms such as tax credits, loan guarantees, and gap loans, have been more critical than ever.</p>

<p>Tony Smith, AICP, of S.B. Friedman Development Advisors will discuss the principles of "when and how to TIF," sharing case studies and approaches for getting the deal done. He will cover the new applications of public/private financing that have emerged since the recession and suggest lessons learned from these applications.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 14:20:29 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/TuesdaysatAPAChicago-ClosingtheGap.mp3" length="73704688" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CC906B17-DE75-433E-B378-F404B17B392D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://media.planning.org/apa_647_sd_300.jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CicLAvia - Opening the Streets for Pedestrians in Los Angeles</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA talks with Aaron Paley about the CicLAvia bicycle and pedestrian event in Los Angeles.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 10:48:37 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/CicLAvia.mp3" length="25630430" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">05E2747E-87BD-404F-B83C-634D516956DC</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Waters Elementary: A Sustainable Schoolyard in Chicago</title>
            <description><![CDATA[APA's Kids' Planning Toolbox blog editor Rana Salzmann visited Waters Elementary School on the northwest side of Chicago to hear from Ecology Program Coordinator Pete Leki, who has been involved with Waters for more than 20 years.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 11:45:39 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/media/video/Waters_mobile.mp4" length="119908369" type="video/mpeg-4"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2CC8A233-84DB-416C-A5B9-7D1DEF5B99B7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>14:14</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning Los Angeles</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Timothy Mennel, editor of APA Planners Press, interviews editor David C. Sloane and contributors Todd Gish and Andrew Whittemore, on their newest book, Planning Los Angeles.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 15:05:23 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://media.planning.org/podcast/Planning_LosAngeles.mp3" length="34321359" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">23707A59-A765-4562-AC12-DA64F3C2DFBD</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>28:32</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Orleans Recovery: A Social Science Perspective</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Jim Schwab, Manager of the kAPA Hazards Planning Research Center and editor of the Recovery News blog, interviews Shirley Laska, PhD. and Kristina Peterson, PhD., from the Center for Hazards Assessment, Response, and Technology at The University of New Orleans (UNO-CHART).]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 10:48:11 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/JHuDERhoSX4/Schwab-NOLARecovery.mp3" length="29872272" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4421FD2A-7BA1-4CCD-966E-F37950E199D6</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>Jim Schwab, Manager of the kAPA Hazards Planning Research Center and editor of the Recovery News blog, interviews Shirley Laska, PhD. and Kristina Peterson, PhD., from the Center for Hazards Assessment, Response, and Technology at The University of New Or</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Jim Schwab, Manager of the kAPA Hazards Planning Research Center and editor of the Recovery News blog, interviews Shirley Laska, PhD. and Kristina Peterson, PhD., from the Center for Hazards Assessment, Response, and Technology at The University of New Orleans (UNO-CHART).</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>31:03</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA Chicago: Mobility Networks in the Americas: Local Politics and Cultural Paradigms</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Mobility Networks in the Americas: Local Politics and Cultural Paradigms
<br />March 13, 2012</p>

<p>As cities in Latin America take the lead in developing innovative, cost-effective transportation networks, such as Bus Rapid Transit, outcomes have shown how local politics and culture shape each system differently.</p>

<p>Building on previous work in Colombia and New York City, Andrea Marpillero-Colomina, from Columbia University, and Thomas Bassett, from the American Planning Association, discussed recent field research in Santiago, Chile, where the government has recently implemented a new bus system. Like others in the region, this system has been confronted by substantial planning challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 16:43:28 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/vvwDvUHr5oo/tuesapachicago-mobilityamericas.mp3" length="65825765" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">07DACD4B-C507-4CC0-B177-5D0B9859668B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Mobility Networks in the Americas: Local Politics and Cultural Paradigms March 13, 2012 As cities in Latin America take the lead in developing innovative, cost-effective transportation networks, such as Bus Rapid Transit, outcomes have shown how local po</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Mobility Networks in the Americas: Local Politics and Cultural Paradigms March 13, 2012 As cities in Latin America take the lead in developing innovative, cost-effective transportation networks, such as Bus Rapid Transit, outcomes have shown how local politics and culture shape each system differently. Building on previous work in Colombia and New York City, Andrea Marpillero-Colomina, from Columbia University, and Thomas Bassett, from the American Planning Association, discussed recent field research in Santiago, Chile, where the government has recently implemented a new bus system. Like others in the region, this system has been confronted by substantial planning challenges.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:47</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Redfield to Redevelopment in Libertyville, Illinois</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Redfield to Redevelopment in Libertyville, Illinois
<br />February 21, 2012</p>

<p>The newly minted term redfield refers to financially distressed development projects (i.e., properties in the red). As a result of the Great Recession, few communities are immune to the negative effects of redfields. The relatively affluent community of Libertyville, Illinois, felt the sting when plans for high-end townhomes and the adaptive reuse of a decommissioned elementary school near the village's vibrant downtown went bust in 2008. Then in 2010 Libertyville-based developer John McLinden negotiated purchase of the bank-owned site and secured approval from the Village for the new urbanist SchoolStreet development.</p>

<p>At build out, SchoolStreet will feature 26 single-family homes designed to blend with the historic turn-of-the-century homes in the neighborhood in addition to urban lofts in the preserved school. Apart from the project's prime location near downtown and a commuter rail station, another key to the project's success has been an architect-guided design process that allows buyers to customize their homes without adding to final costs.</p>

<p>John Spoden, AICP, from the Village of Libertyville and John McLinden from StreetScape Development discussed the details of the SchoolStreet project and explained how this project supports the village's long-term vision for growth and change.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 11:25:33 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/S2ntdhpKmfk/tuesapachicago-redfield.mp3" length="51399100" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BEEC5199-5865-4828-BA5B-F0C48F2C7438</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Redfield to Redevelopment in Libertyville, Illinois February 21, 2012 The newly minted term redfield refers to financially distressed development projects (i.e., properties in the red). As a result of the Great Recession, few communities are immune to th</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>53:32</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA-DC: Travel Behavior, Transport Policy, and Sustainable Transport in Germany and the U.S</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Travel Behavior, Transport Policy, and Sustainable Transport in Germany and the USA
<br />February 21, 2012</p>

<p>Reliance on the automobile for most trips contributes to costly trends like pollution, oil dependence, congestion, and obesity. Germany and the U.S. have among the highest motorization rates in the world. Yet Germans make a four times higher share of trips by foot, bike, and public transport and drive for a 25 percent lower share of trips.</p>

<p>This presentation investigated daily travel behavior in the two countries and then examined the transport and land-use policies in Germany over the last 40 years that have encouraged more walking, bicycling, and public transport use.</p>

<p>Using a case study of policy changes in the German city of Freiburg, Ralph Buehler identified policies that are transferable to car-oriented countries around the world.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 11:24:33 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/tAkNRTMB7l8/tuesapadc-germantransport.mp3" length="58345193" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4033552E-A4C2-420F-B4E0-9A1076AFA0EC</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Travel Behavior, Transport Policy, and Sustainable Transport in Germany and the USA February 21, 2012 Reliance on the automobile for most trips contributes to costly trends like pollution, oil dependence, congestion, and obesity. Germany and the U.S. hav</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:00:46</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Planning for and with Ecosystem Services</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Planning for and with Ecosystem Services
<br />January 24, 2012</p>

<p>Because all communities benefit from resources and processes supplied by natural ecosystems, ecology can be an important lens for viewing planning and site design. While many planners support and philosophically align with LEED, SITES, and the growing ecological design culture, they may feel ill-equipped to apply scientific findings to planning projects.</p>

<p>Jacob Blue from Applied Ecological Services explored how science can inform planning decisions from the planner's and scientist's perspectives and provided planners with basic, practical tools for incorporating ecological decisions into their work.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 11:21:41 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/dCfH1_SwYho/tuesapa-ecosystemservices.mp3" length="62477925" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E1830586-8D83-427B-8430-B077FD7CD844</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Planning for and with Ecosystem Services January 24, 2012 Because all communities benefit from resources and processes supplied by natural ecosystems, ecology can be an important lens for viewing planning and site design. While many planners support and </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:05:04</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rebuilding Greensburg: Four Years of Progress</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Greensburg, Kansas, Mayor Bob Dixson, and Stephen Hardy, senior planner with BNIM Architects in Kansas City, who prepared Greensburg’s Sustainable Comprehensive Plan following the May 2007 tornado that devastated the community, talk with Jim Schwab about the city’s four-year-old efforts to rebuild the community on green principles.</p>

<p>The accompanying photo gallery consists of dozens of images captured by Jim Schwab during a June 2010 meeting in which Greensburg officials and citizens hosted representatives of several communities struck by tornadoes in the spring of 2010, so that they could learn how Greensburg developed its green recovery vision.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 11:20:37 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/cag2e50RF5c/greensburg.mp3" length="27235177" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BB9BF0F0-D3D1-40C2-9469-E26D9F098DF3</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Greensburg, Kansas, Mayor Bob Dixson, and Stephen Hardy, senior planner with BNIM Architects in Kansas City, who prepared Greensburg’s Sustainable Comprehensive Plan following the May 2007 tornado that devastated the community, talk with Jim Schwab about</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Greensburg, Kansas, Mayor Bob Dixson, and Stephen Hardy, senior planner with BNIM Architects in Kansas City, who prepared Greensburg’s Sustainable Comprehensive Plan following the May 2007 tornado that devastated the community, talk with Jim Schwab about the city’s four-year-old efforts to rebuild the community on green principles. The accompanying photo gallery consists of dozens of images captured by Jim Schwab during a June 2010 meeting in which Greensburg officials and citizens hosted representatives of several communities struck by tornadoes in the spring of 2010, so that they could learn how Greensburg developed its green recovery vision.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>28:22</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Prioritizing Green Infrastructure Investment</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Prioritizing Green Infrastructure Investments
<br />November 29, 2011</p>

<p>FCommunity decision makers are increasingly looking at installing green infrastructure to address stormwater issues. To be able to retrofit private property with such natural stormwater solutions, there needs to be a mechanism that can gain private sector involvement and investment.</p>

<p>One approach is to use an auction system, where landowners learn about the economic value of stormwater best management practices (BMPs) and then participate in an auction to bid on what BMPs they are willing to pay for.</p>

<p>Megan Lewis, AICP, of Cardno JFNew, and Sabina Shaikh of RCF Economic and Financial Consulting, described a project conducted for the City of Valparaiso, Indiana, to help that community prioritize stormwater BMP installation in a specific neighborhood.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 11:18:27 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/nHaBpNQxezg/tuesapa-greeninfrastructure.mp3" length="50794298" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">226ED62F-C2B1-419B-9C51-100F7130CE4F</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Prioritizing Green Infrastructure Investments November 29, 2011 FCommunity decision makers are increasingly looking at installing green infrastructure to address stormwater issues. To be able to retrofit private property with such natural stormwater solu</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>52:54</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Neighbors and Neighborhoods: An Interview with Sidney Brower</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this podcast, Sidney Brower, author of Neighbors & Neighborhoods: Elements of Successful Community Design, discuss the connection between community design and the ability of residents to come together as a community.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 11:15:49 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/xQOn3mztEbo/sidneybrower.mp3" length="17468322" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3637CC11-EB6C-409F-8E01-EB8E4B7CD018</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>In this podcast, Sidney Brower, author of Neighbors &amp; Neighborhoods: Elements of Successful Community Design, discuss the connection between community design and the ability of residents to come together as a community.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>In this podcast, Sidney Brower, author of Neighbors &amp; Neighborhoods: Elements of Successful Community Design, discuss the connection between community design and the ability of residents to come together as a community.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>18:11</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2011 AICP Symposium</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>2011 AICP Symposium
<br />Cities in Transition: Today's Realities and the Next Economies
<br />October 27, 2011
<br />9:30 a.m.–12:00 noon
<br />National Building Museum
<br />Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Cities are always transitioning, requiring planners to reinvent techniques for new economic development. This year's AICP Symposium will provide examples of initiatives from around the country that are creating opportunities for effective and equitable development.</p>

<p>Speakers</p>

<p>Carolina Barco
<br />Former Ambassador of Colombia to the United States</p>

<p>Robert N. Brown
<br />Director, City Planning Commission
<br />Cleveland, Ohio</p>

<p>Jay Williams
<br />Executive Director, Office of Recovery for Auto Communities and Workers</p>

<p>Jason Jordan, moderator
<br />American Planning Association
<br />Director of Policy and Government Affairs</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 11:05:53 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/856e3ahufNg/2011-aicp-symposium.mp3" length="140425603" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5941D1D1-B8D5-444F-B077-0FBF398DDE48</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> 2011 AICP Symposium Cities in Transition: Today's Realities and the Next Economies October 27, 2011 9:30 a.m.–12:00 noon National Building Museum Washington, D.C. Cities are always transitioning, requiring planners to reinvent techniques for new economic</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> 2011 AICP Symposium Cities in Transition: Today's Realities and the Next Economies October 27, 2011 9:30 a.m.–12:00 noon National Building Museum Washington, D.C. Cities are always transitioning, requiring planners to reinvent techniques for new economic development. This year's AICP Symposium will provide examples of initiatives from around the country that are creating opportunities for effective and equitable development. Speakers Carolina Barco Former Ambassador of Colombia to the United States Robert N. Brown Director, City Planning Commission Cleveland, Ohio Jay Williams Executive Director, Office of Recovery for Auto Communities and Workers Jason Jordan, moderator American Planning Association Director of Policy and Government Affairs</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>2:26:16</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2011 L'Enfant Lecture on City Planning and Deisgn with Marilyn Taylor</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>2011 Lecture
<br />Tuesday, October 25, 2011 
<br />San Francisco</p>

<p>Planning, Policy, and Poetics:
<br />Reviving Investment in Transportation and Infrastructure in America
<br />Marilyn Taylor
<br />Dean of the University of Pennsylvania School of Design</p>

<p>The 2011 L'Enfant Lecture was delivered by Marilyn Taylor, who became dean of The School of Design at the University of Pennsylvania in October 2008 after practicing as an architect and urban designer at Skidmore Owings & Merrill.</p>

<p>Taylor spoke on "Planning, Policy, and Poetics: Reviving Investment in Transportation and Infrastructure in America." Can we, as designers and planners, help rekindle a sense of stewardship for the future and rebuild the public will needed to stimulate investment? What does this mean for planners and, perhaps more importantly, for planning education?</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 10:58:43 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Trz0yQe-tfY/lenfant2011.mp3" length="52684318" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6B35713F-3C45-4C8D-851A-8CC52D190A2D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> 2011 Lecture Tuesday, October 25, 2011 San Francisco Planning, Policy, and Poetics: Reviving Investment in Transportation and Infrastructure in America Marilyn Taylor Dean of the University of Pennsylvania School of Design The 2011 L'Enfant Lecture was d</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> 2011 Lecture Tuesday, October 25, 2011 San Francisco Planning, Policy, and Poetics: Reviving Investment in Transportation and Infrastructure in America Marilyn Taylor Dean of the University of Pennsylvania School of Design The 2011 L'Enfant Lecture was delivered by Marilyn Taylor, who became dean of The School of Design at the University of Pennsylvania in October 2008 after practicing as an architect and urban designer at Skidmore Owings &amp; Merrill. Taylor spoke on "Planning, Policy, and Poetics: Reviving Investment in Transportation and Infrastructure in America." Can we, as designers and planners, help rekindle a sense of stewardship for the future and rebuild the public will needed to stimulate investment? What does this mean for planners and, perhaps more importantly, for planning education?</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:52</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cedar Rapids Flood Recovery: An Interview with Christine Butterfield</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Christine Butterfield is the director of community development for the city of Cedar Rapids, Iowa, which was hit by a record-breaking flood in June 2008. She speaks here about the extensive planning effort to rebuild a city in which more than 10,000 people were evacuated from areas along the Cedar River, historic neighborhoods were inundated, and thousands of residents lost their homes or saw them badly damaged.</p>

<p>At the APA National Planning Conference in Boston in April 2011, she and her staff saw the city’s heroic efforts recognized with an APA National Planning Excellence Award for Best Practices in Hazard Mitigation and Disaster Planning, shared with Sasaki Associates, Inc., for the city’s new River Corridor Development Plan.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 10:46:07 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/3JCBXgX2FIY/cedarrapids-butterfield.mp3" length="10273607" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">92F146B2-0032-4EB2-86C5-48F1D8E20DA7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Christine Butterfield is the director of community development for the city of Cedar Rapids, Iowa, which was hit by a record-breaking flood in June 2008. She speaks here about the extensive planning effort to rebuild a city in which more than 10,000 peop</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Christine Butterfield is the director of community development for the city of Cedar Rapids, Iowa, which was hit by a record-breaking flood in June 2008. She speaks here about the extensive planning effort to rebuild a city in which more than 10,000 people were evacuated from areas along the Cedar River, historic neighborhoods were inundated, and thousands of residents lost their homes or saw them badly damaged. At the APA National Planning Conference in Boston in April 2011, she and her staff saw the city’s heroic efforts recognized with an APA National Planning Excellence Award for Best Practices in Hazard Mitigation and Disaster Planning, shared with Sasaki Associates, Inc., for the city’s new River Corridor Development Plan.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>10:42</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Planning and Zoning for Natural Resource Protection</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Planning and Zoning for Natural Resource Protection
<br />September 27, 2011</p>

<p>In recent decades, planners have continued to be involved in natural resource protection as a core area of both interest and expertise. However, in many places, mitigation takes precedence over more meaningful efforts to avoid or minimize environmental damage. When wetlands are disturbed or mature trees replaced with seedlings, it may take decades for the natural system to return to its prior value, and in terms of net carbon emissions, the debt may never be repaid.</p>

<p>Now that planners are taking a renewed interest in sustainability, the time is right to rediscover planning and zoning principles to protect natural resources.</p>

<p>Lane Kendig, founder of Kendig Keast Collaborative, discussed how planners can use performance zoning for resource protection.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 10:43:53 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/QWkQKN5hWhg/tuesapa-naturalresourceprotection.mp3" length="55285695" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">764E5FF0-0E22-4FFA-9225-4B4ED124406B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Planning and Zoning for Natural Resource Protection September 27, 2011 In recent decades, planners have continued to be involved in natural resource protection as a core area of both interest and expertise. However, in many places, mitigation takes prece</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>57:35</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kids and Community: An Interview with Roger Hart Part 2</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical environment. He has been particularly concerned with the application of research to the planning and design of children's environments and to environmental education.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 10:42:28 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Lucxwlc4-NM/rogerhart-part2.mp3" length="12010188" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CF08CD8D-9555-407B-BF42-0AEAA77B57CB</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical envi</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical environment. He has been particularly concerned with the application of research to the planning and design of children's environments and to environmental education.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>12:30</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kids and Community: An Interview with Roger Hart Part 1</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical environment. He has been particularly concerned with the application of research to the planning and design of children's environments and to environmental education.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 10:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/84W3VQsNlz4/rogerhart-part1.mp3" length="15813198" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1598B5EE-8E03-49A7-9A69-9E1CC7BE5ABF</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical envi</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Roger Hart and Ramona Mullahy in conversation. Hart is co-director of the Children's Environments Research Group at the City University of New York. His work focuses on the development of theory and research on children's relationship to the physical environment. He has been particularly concerned with the application of research to the planning and design of children's environments and to environmental education.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>16:28</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Role of Planning in Stabalizing Distressed Properties</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Role of Planning in Stabilizing Distressed Properties
<br />August 30, 2011</p>

<p>Many communities have a glut of entitled but unfinished development projects. Depending on the context and scale of the problem, traditional stabilization tools such as code enforcement may prove inadequate or ineffective. In some cases, the best solution for the community may involve relaxing certain regulatory requirements or renegotiating the terms of development agreements.</p>

<p>Daniel Shapiro from Robbins, Salomon & Patt and Jessica Schramm from Thompson Coburn discussed a wide range of strategies planners can use to stabilize and reposition distressed properties. Specific strategies covered will include reviewing agreements recorded against property, negotiating development fees, and re-entitling property. They also addressed how planners can assist when development deals turn sour.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 10:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/OOK5n2weS2M/tuesapa-distressedproperties.mp3" length="57985717" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1754D696-37C4-4AA0-98B5-3FA2818118D7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> The Role of Planning in Stabilizing Distressed Properties August 30, 2011 Many communities have a glut of entitled but unfinished development projects. Depending on the context and scale of the problem, traditional stabilization tools such as code enforc</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:00:24</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: The Patchwork Quilt - An Interview with Edward Thomas and Alessandra Jerolleman</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 10:38:30 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/iENP9Sd-b-U/postdisaster2011-patchworkquilt.mp3" length="25706344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B9E21925-5DFB-425E-95BB-AE9A2AE59298</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>26:46</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reconsidering Jane Jacobs: A Discussion with Max Page, Rudayna Abdo, and Jamin Creed Rowan</title>
            <description><![CDATA[How did one woman change an entire profession in a few short years with such lasting effects? Listen as Max Page, co-editor of Reconsidering Jane Jacobs, discusses Jane Jacobs's lasting, global influence. Joining Page are contributors Rudayna Abdo, AICP, director of planning at Otak International's Abu Dhabi office, and Jamin Creed Rowan, assistant professor of English at Brigham Young University.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 10:37:36 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/5tz5oCsNIzA/janejacobs.mp3" length="33979411" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F5E61F99-4717-4C82-8A42-D8A065797780</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>How did one woman change an entire profession in a few short years with such lasting effects? Listen as Max Page, co-editor of Reconsidering Jane Jacobs, discusses Jane Jacobs's lasting, global influence. Joining Page are contributors Rudayna Abdo, AICP, </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>How did one woman change an entire profession in a few short years with such lasting effects? Listen as Max Page, co-editor of Reconsidering Jane Jacobs, discusses Jane Jacobs's lasting, global influence. Joining Page are contributors Rudayna Abdo, AICP, director of planning at Otak International's Abu Dhabi office, and Jamin Creed Rowan, assistant professor of English at Brigham Young University.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>35:23</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA-DC: Arlington County's "Community Energy Plan"</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Arlington County's "Community Energy Plan"
<br />July 12, 2011</p>

<p>Arlington County's "Community Energy Plan" is a strategic planning effort to ensure economic competitiveness and energy supply security while reinforcing the county's environmental commitment. Through this process Arlington will transform the way it generates, distributes, stores, and uses energy.</p>

<p>A nationally recognized leader in climate action, Arlington County is working to reduce energy use and greenhouse gas emissions from government operations through the Arlington Initiative to Reduce Emissions (AIRE) program. The county has broadened that effort into the community to chart a course toward a healthy, viable, sustainable Arlington for generations to come.</p>

<p>The plan aims to sharply reduce energy use in Arlington, including an ambitious goal of reducing greenhouse gas emissions by more than 70 percent by 2050.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 10:35:35 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Mfeu_QkCoig/tuesapadc-arlingtonenergy.mp3" length="71655478" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F6FD4559-7C93-48E0-A13D-A962083F6A27</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Arlington County's "Community Energy Plan" July 12, 2011 Arlington County's "Community Energy Plan" is a strategic planning effort to ensure economic competitiveness and energy supply security while reinforcing the county's environmental commitment. Thro</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:14:38</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Tools for Great Lakes Planners in NOAA's Digital Coast</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Tools for Great Lakes Planners in NOAA's Digital Coast
<br />July 19, 2011</p>

<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's Digital Coast partnership provides data, tools, and training on topics such as land use, coastal conservation, hazards, marine spatial planning, and climate change. Recently, planners in the Great Lakes have participated in two needs assessments to help build new tools and improve datasets and training courses for climate change adaptation and conservation planning.</p>

<p>Panelists from APA, NOAA, and the Old Woman Creek National Estuarine Research Reserve presented the results of these assessments and shared how you can use some of the new tools and datasets in your community. Products featured included climate adaptation training for planners, easy-to-use land cover and elevation data, and a publicly available visualization tool.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 10:34:33 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/iHFFfl_006c/tuesapa-digitalcoast.mp3" length="62967369" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4CF6F2D1-E245-46E2-AD54-48F029C6BB80</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Tools for Great Lakes Planners in NOAA's Digital Coast July 19, 2011 The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's Digital Coast partnership provides data, tools, and training on topics such as land use, coastal conservation, hazards, marine spat</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:05:35</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: Lincoln Walther</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 10:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/z_yqn8YK_ts/postdisaster2011-lincolnwalther.mp3" length="22773461" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">21414388-E152-4B57-9721-BD9C4C0A353D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>23:43</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA-DC: Re-Planning Crystal City As a 21st Century Urban Village</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Re-Planning Crystal City As a 21st Century Urban Village
<br />April 26, 2011</p>

<p>The 2006 Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) action hit Arlington, Virginia, hard. The loss of 17,000 Department of Defense employees and 4.2 million square feet of leased space was the equivalent of losing five military bases, and most of the impact was in the Crystal City neighborhood. Developed largely in the 1960s and 1970s, Crystal City contained approximately 30 buildings aged 30 years or more, originally built to GSA specifications that not longer reflected the needs of the market. Arlington developed a plan to remove the older office buildings, add more than 30 new buildings, increase density by more than 60 percent, and substantially improve transportation and the entire urban environment.</p>

<p>This discussion will address the planning process, the economic and transportation analyses that served as the basis of the plan, and the innovative financing plan developed to pay for the necessary infrastructure to make the plan a reality.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 10:32:12 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/ElaSWBzjM9M/tuesapa-dc-crystalcity.mp3" length="71651296" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">44B6B492-EEE9-47A7-B64C-3D8B90A7427D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Re-Planning Crystal City As a 21st Century Urban Village April 26, 2011 The 2006 Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) action hit Arlington, Virginia, hard. The loss of 17,000 Department of Defense employees and 4.2 million square feet of leased space was </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:14:38</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Implementing Sustainable Cities in a Harsh Environment (Lessons from Masdar)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Implementing Sustainable Cities in a Harsh Environment: Some Lessons Learned from Masdar
<br />June 21, 2011</p>

<p>Masdar City in the United Arab Emirates is envisioned as the world's first carbon-neutral, zero waste, car-free city. However, the harsh, desert environment and the prevailing planning and construction practices in Abu Dhabi pose special challenges for an inherently ambitious goal.</p>

<p>Margaret Cederoth, AICP, will discuss the specific elements of sustainable cities incorporated into the plans for Masdar and the practical methods for implementing these ambitions in the first few buildings of the city. The presentation will highlight relevant master plan elements that are the foundation for sustainability and focus on the physical expression of those elements along with basic contractual and education activities necessary to realize the vision.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 10:28:57 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/My05T8Bq8h4/tuesapa-masdar.mp3" length="52490827" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FBD6F8B3-FC02-4826-B752-7A3F1AE56CF5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Implementing Sustainable Cities in a Harsh Environment: Some Lessons Learned from Masdar June 21, 2011 Masdar City in the United Arab Emirates is envisioned as the world's first carbon-neutral, zero waste, car-free city. However, the harsh, desert enviro</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>54:40</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: David Godschalk and Gerald Jones</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 10:27:14 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/lW0Ow1-yGXg/postdisaster2011-godschalk-jones.mp3" length="20534052" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BC0F7669-DE53-443F-B0E6-C0CE01ECE551</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>21:23</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Recycling in Chicago: Past, Present, and Future</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Recycling in Chicago: Past, Present, and Future
<br />May 17, 2011</p>

<p>As Chicago begins a new political era, much attention has been paid to the problems in Chicago's recycling program. Carl Zimring from Roosevelt University analyzed the public and private systems used to recycle post-consumer materials in Chicago over the past century, with discussion of how the current system evolved, problems with it, and ways in which future versions of recycling in Chicago might work based on historical precedents and programs in other cities.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 10:26:30 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Y1dnzFrd4tw/tuesapa-chirecycling.mp3" length="63896041" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">16DFEE6C-22D8-4621-90E7-B9E30FCEA387</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Recycling in Chicago: Past, Present, and Future May 17, 2011 As Chicago begins a new political era, much attention has been paid to the problems in Chicago's recycling program. Carl Zimring from Roosevelt University analyzed the public and private system</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:06:33</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: Barry Hokanson</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 10:24:56 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/a1SqX0uEo1c/postdisaster2011-barryhokanson.mp3" length="16453917" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">15549BEF-4997-4A49-8945-43E4628DE0B1</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>17:08</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: David Miller and Gavin Smith</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 10:22:21 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/s13rzGKoscI/postdisaster2011-millersmith.mp3" length="23585150" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9DB6AFBF-F2A7-433C-BCB7-F0A3B86F78ED</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>24:34</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Future of Youth Engagement in Planning: An Interview with Barry Checkoway</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In this podcast, Barry Checkoway and Ramona Mullahey discuss "The Future of Youth Engagement in Planning." Checkoway is a professor of social work and urban planning at the University of Michigan. He previously worked with the White House in launching AmeriCorps. Checkoway and Mullahey, along with Yve Susskind, are the authors of PAS Report 486, Youth Participation in Community Planning.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 10:20:59 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/hsTjziU_D8s/mullahey-barrycheckoway.mp3" length="21848133" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">89F7D433-ACB6-4332-8223-480939DFDBDC</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>In this podcast, Barry Checkoway and Ramona Mullahey discuss "The Future of Youth Engagement in Planning." Checkoway is a professor of social work and urban planning at the University of Michigan. He previously worked with the White House in launching Ame</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>In this podcast, Barry Checkoway and Ramona Mullahey discuss "The Future of Youth Engagement in Planning." Checkoway is a professor of social work and urban planning at the University of Michigan. He previously worked with the White House in launching AmeriCorps. Checkoway and Mullahey, along with Yve Susskind, are the authors of PAS Report 486, Youth Participation in Community Planning.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>22:45</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: Ken Topping and Laurie Johnson</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 10:17:55 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/yq_NnnhJiW0/postdisaster2011-johnson-topping.mp3" length="25969192" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">113CB1B6-7053-4861-9579-C6AA2FE61C6A</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>27:03</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Plight of Black Coastal Land Owners in the Sunbelt South</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Plight of Black Coastal Landowners in the Sunbelt South and Its Lessons for Post–Housing Bubble America
<br />April 26, 2011</p>

<p>At the turn of the 20th century, African Americans owned vast swaths of property along America's shores. By the post–World War II era, African American beaches and resorts served as important places for working families to escape from the daily indignities of Jim Crow and for a separate, seasonal black leisure economy to take shape. The death of Jim Crow coincided with the emergence of a pro-growth, corporate-friendly Sunbelt economy, which led to massive resort and residential development in coastal areas, and the targeting of black coastal landowners as the path of least resistance.</p>

<p>From the 1960s to the present, African American property owners in areas targeted for leisure-based economic and real estate development have struggled to fend off various schemes deployed by developers and their allies in municipal, county, and state governments to expropriate and put to "best use" valuable property.</p>

<p>Andrew Kahrl from Marquette University examined the legal instruments of real estate development, black land loss, and the privatization of public space in coastal areas in modern America, its relation to broader changes in the coastal and global economies, and its social and environmental implications.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 10:16:45 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/cLXlRl0bf20/tuesapa-blackcoastal.mp3" length="59935500" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BEEA8984-35EB-4905-924C-1AA0FC68226C</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> The Plight of Black Coastal Landowners in the Sunbelt South and Its Lessons for Post–Housing Bubble America April 26, 2011 At the turn of the 20th century, African Americans owned vast swaths of property along America's shores. By the post–World War II e</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> The Plight of Black Coastal Landowners in the Sunbelt South and Its Lessons for Post–Housing Bubble America April 26, 2011 At the turn of the 20th century, African Americans owned vast swaths of property along America's shores. By the post–World War II era, African American beaches and resorts served as important places for working families to escape from the daily indignities of Jim Crow and for a separate, seasonal black leisure economy to take shape. The death of Jim Crow coincided with the emergence of a pro-growth, corporate-friendly Sunbelt economy, which led to massive resort and residential development in coastal areas, and the targeting of black coastal landowners as the path of least resistance. From the 1960s to the present, African American property owners in areas targeted for leisure-based economic and real estate development have struggled to fend off various schemes deployed by developers and their allies in municipal, county, and state governments to expropriate and put to "best use" valuable property. Andrew Kahrl from Marquette University examined the legal instruments of real estate development, black land loss, and the privatization of public space in coastal areas in modern America, its relation to broader changes in the coastal and global economies, and its social and environmental implications.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:02:25</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for Post Disaster: FEMA</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery</p>

<p>On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 10:09:48 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/OmjvjuVeRDg/postdisaster2011-fema.mp3" length="19941808" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C6776D9D-097C-402F-9E3D-292FAAC027AD</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Symposium on Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery On February 10–11, 2011, the American Planning Association hosted a scoping symposium in its Chicago office to explore a number of essential issues in guiding the Planning for Post-Disaster Recovery: Next Generation project as it moves forward. Invited participants focused on helping APA to define the appropriate audiences and central issues for the project, delineate the guiding principles in planning for post-disaster recovery, refine the outline for the PAS Report, and identify criteria for best practices and potential case examples to study.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>20:46</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ethics_Session_2011-Boston</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 09:53:32 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/aS_4f3UllSk/ethics_session_2011-boston.mp3" length="37341149" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CD8118E9-E764-4972-8185-F656146E8FF6</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>38:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Sustaining Place</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Sustaining Places
<br />March 22, 2011</p>

<p>In March 2010, APA President Bruce Knight, FAICP, introduced APA’s Sustaining Places Initiative at the United Nations Fifth World Forum.</p>

<p>In his remarks, he explained, "Sustaining Places will examine both how places can be sustained and how places themselves sustain life and civilizations. Planning's comprehensive focus is not limited to a building or a site but encompasses all scales and all forms of organization of human settlements, from rural areas and small town to cities and metropolitan regions. Planners are uniquely qualified to be global leaders in integrating these two concepts of sustainability and places. Ours is the place-making profession and the places that we make must have lasting value for all."</p>

<p>Knight's Tuesdays at APA presentation took a closer look at the Sustaining Places Initiative and its focus on positioning the comprehensive plan as the primary local sustainability policy tool.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 09:49:39 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/vdIbPlvrctM/tuesapa-sustainingplaces.mp3" length="47869811" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D0ED355C-805F-4A39-A3C1-95234FB69F93</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Sustaining Places March 22, 2011 In March 2010, APA President Bruce Knight, FAICP, introduced APA’s Sustaining Places Initiative at the United Nations Fifth World Forum. In his remarks, he explained, "Sustaining Places will examine both how places can be</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>49:51</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Gary and Region Investment Project</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Gary and Region Investment Project
<br />March 15, 2011</p>

<p>Gary and other urban areas in Northwest Indiana have weathered decades of disinvestment. Yet they possess significant — if underused — assets, including national parks, miles of Lake Michigan shoreline, transit hubs, historic landmarks, and a strong workforce. While it would make a natural poster child for what is often called "right-sizing," this region is often overshadowed by cities like Detroit, Flint, and Youngstown in this emerging national dialogue.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, the Gary and Region Investment Project (GRIP) is an important sign of how Northwest Indiana is crafting a regional approach to forward key transformative projects with the aim of stabilizing and reinvesting in the urban core.</p>

<p>Joanna Trotter from the Metropolitan Planning Council and Hubert Morgan from the Northwest Indiana Regional Planning commission gave an overview of GRIP and provided an update on progress to date.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 09:47:36 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/L0KQw23V264/tuesapa-garyinvestment.mp3" length="63488545" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B75F30C5-22C2-4FAF-8AB2-B3D7787C005D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Gary and Region Investment Project March 15, 2011 Gary and other urban areas in Northwest Indiana have weathered decades of disinvestment. Yet they possess significant — if underused — assets, including national parks, miles of Lake Michigan shoreline, t</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:06:08</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>APA Boston Conference Preview: Bob Mitchell</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 09:45:49 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/-vd4Uo-q384/boston-bobmitchell.mp3" length="9193549" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BD5D2DDD-9E6A-4EFF-AC6F-D4CE46973AA5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>9:34</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>APA Boston Conference Preview: Peter Lowitt</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 09:45:23 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/KKrNzT-iWXU/boston-peterlowitt.mp3" length="9101598" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2E8981A0-6000-4E91-AAA5-E9272394B59B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>9:28</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>APA Boston Conference Preview: Jennifer Raitt</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 09:45:01 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/yYx4yVJFM4Y/boston-jenniferraitt.mp3" length="11969218" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AD29C091-6CF2-49AC-890F-65846942DD49</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>12:28</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Community Reinvestment and the Foreclosure Crisis</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Community Reinvestment and the Foreclosure Crisis
<br />February 22, 2011</p>

<p>According to the Woodstock Institute, lenders repossessed more than 25,000 homes in the Chicago area during the first three quarters of 2010. According to the same analysis, these lender-owned foreclosures will take an average of 16 months to be absorbed by the housing market. Vacant properties cause blight, which destabilizes neighborhoods and local real estate markets, and also weakens the ability of municipalities to maintain a comfortable quality of life by shrinking tax rolls and increasing maintenance costs.</p>

<p>Geoff Smith from the Woodstock Institute took an in-depth look at recent trends in foreclosure activity in the Chicago region with a focus on the shifting patterns of regional foreclosures, the concentration of vacant properties tied to foreclosures, and implications for community development.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 09:38:27 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/4yTQY9ctAfk/tuesapa-foreclosurecrisis.mp3" length="57572765" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">851C2519-D5CF-45B5-BE9F-B87EA236D196</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Community Reinvestment and the Foreclosure Crisis February 22, 2011 According to the Woodstock Institute, lenders repossessed more than 25,000 homes in the Chicago area during the first three quarters of 2010. According to the same analysis, these lender</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>59:58</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: A Template for Redeveloping Chicago's Neighborhoods</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A Template for Redeveloping Chicago's Neighborhoods
<br />January 25, 2011</p>

<p>According to Bruce Frankel, a Professor of Urban Planning at Ball State, neighborhood reinvestment depends on distinct strategies based on neighborhood conditions, both assets and liabilities. In essence, a redeveloper must select the neighborhood for the strategy, and vice-versa.</p>

<p>Frankel and his students explained this strategy/conditions matrix and explored how these strategic plans become financially underwritten and structured to be financially sustainable. To illustrate the model in action, Frankel and his students presented a strategy for the Bronzeville neighborhood in Chicago.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 09:36:19 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/KUOhggvYlw0/tuesapa-redevelopingchicago.mp3" length="73051468" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">668849C2-4678-4A50-AF89-79802F4F90BA</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> A Template for Redeveloping Chicago's Neighborhoods January 25, 2011 According to Bruce Frankel, a Professor of Urban Planning at Ball State, neighborhood reinvestment depends on distinct strategies based on neighborhood conditions, both assets and liabi</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:16:05</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Paradox of Urban Space: An Interview with Sharon Sutton</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Professor Sharon Sutton has had a long career in developing youth engagement programs with a special interest in involving minority and disenfranchised youth. </p>

<p>Professor Sutton is interviewed in this podcast by Ramona Mullahey, editor of ResoucesZine APA's electronic publication on youth engagement. They discuss Sutton's new book, The Paradox of Urban Space: Inequity and Transformation in Marginalized Communities.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 09:34:24 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/FjUr8bzkamM/paradoxofurbanspace.mp3" length="29428223" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">49710A55-5B4C-427A-A7E0-895E0DFEE43D</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Professor Sharon Sutton has had a long career in developing youth engagement programs with a special interest in involving minority and disenfranchised youth. Professor Sutton is interviewed in this podcast by Ramona Mullahey, editor of ResoucesZine APA'</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Professor Sharon Sutton has had a long career in developing youth engagement programs with a special interest in involving minority and disenfranchised youth. Professor Sutton is interviewed in this podcast by Ramona Mullahey, editor of ResoucesZine APA's electronic publication on youth engagement. They discuss Sutton's new book, The Paradox of Urban Space: Inequity and Transformation in Marginalized Communities.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>30:39</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Cultural Resource Protection</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Cultural Resource Protection
<br />November 23, 2010</p>

<p>In 1993 the Town of Ithaca, New York, Planning Department and Cornell University collaborated to launch the Inlet Valley Archaeological Survey (IVAS), a pre-emptive cultural resources survey to identify areas of archaeological importance in an area south of Ithaca slated for major development. The IVAS permitted Ithaca's planning department to work with developers to design around and ultimately protect identified historic and cultural resources. George Frantz, AICP, a visiting lecturer at Cornell, will discuss IVAS and explain how it became the genesis of two public parks and a revival of interest in the area's Native American heritage.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 09:32:11 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/zprpm5UJjSo/tuesapa-culturalresourceprotection.mp3" length="49955020" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B3F008C7-5C4E-4A56-BAD5-A898B1FFC966</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Cultural Resource Protection November 23, 2010 In 1993 the Town of Ithaca, New York, Planning Department and Cornell University collaborated to launch the Inlet Valley Archaeological Survey (IVAS), a pre-emptive cultural resources survey to identify area</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>52:02</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Siting and Permitting Wind Farms</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Siting and Permitting Wind Farms
<br />October 19, 2010</p>

<p>DeKalb County, Illinois, recently approved a large, commercial wind farm, the first in the county and the largest single zoning action in its history. The wind farm consists of 151 turbines covering an area of approximately 22,000 acres.</p>

<p>Paul Miller, AICP, from DeKalb County discussed the review process for this proposal, highlighting the issues raised by objectors to the project as well as responses and adopted solutions. His presentation included lessons learned and recommendations for other jurisdictions considering wind farm proposals.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 16:53:44 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/SdeKgSyKnVQ/tuesapa-windfarms.mp3" length="56540807" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">43210DFF-A41F-4B06-8561-B9C14A8BE939</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Siting and Permitting Wind Farms October 19, 2010 DeKalb County, Illinois, recently approved a large, commercial wind farm, the first in the county and the largest single zoning action in its history. The wind farm consists of 151 turbines covering an ar</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>58:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Urban Morphology</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Urban Morphology
<br />August 24, 2010</p>

<p>Urban morphology seeks to understand the spatial structure and character of an urban area by examining its patterns and the process of its development. While urban morphology has been a disciplinary specialization amongst American geographers for years, only in southern Europe, where there was no historical separation of planning and architecture, has the work of urban morphologists been brought to bear in the training of architects.</p>

<p>In the ongoing work of the International Seminar on Urban Form, Christopher Miller, from Judson University, is exploring with his students a more research-oriented approach to the American architectural value in contextual design. Miller shared recent student work that examines questions like: Can typology be used to solve the problem of the big box in a 19th-century fabric? How is morphology a condition for pedestrian connectivity? Can the connectivity inherent in a historic fabric be the prescriptive standard for infill.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 16:47:27 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/YI3f-TWVpYk/tuesapa-urbanmorphology.mp3" length="14645774" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2A524F5D-1B8C-4F8D-9F2C-AC4BE5314077</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Urban Morphology August 24, 2010 Urban morphology seeks to understand the spatial structure and character of an urban area by examining its patterns and the process of its development. While urban morphology has been a disciplinary specialization amongst</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:01</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[2010 National Planning Conference] The Dutch Dialogies: An Interview with Dale Morris and David Waggonner</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dutch Dialogues</p>

<p>Dale Morris of the Royal Netherlands Embassy in Washington, D.C., and David Waggonner of Waggonner and Ball Architects based in New Orleans discuss the purpose and outcomes of the Dutch Dialogues series held in New Orleans. Read about Dutch Dialogues at www.dutchdialogues.com.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 16:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/jbwI_Nf-LPk/dutchdialoguesinterview.mp3" length="9108147" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FD3C74A1-2ECE-41C0-8A70-98CF0699E0E3</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Dutch Dialogues Dale Morris of the Royal Netherlands Embassy in Washington, D.C., and David Waggonner of Waggonner and Ball Architects based in New Orleans discuss the purpose and outcomes of the Dutch Dialogues series held in New Orleans. Read about Dut</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>2010 National Planning Conference</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>37:57</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[2010 National Planning Conference] New Orleans, Moving Forward: An Interview With Stephen Villavaso, FAICP</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>New Orleans Moving Forward</p>

<p>Stephen Villavso, FAICP, of Villavaso & Associates, discusses the current planning status of New Orleans and the future of the city.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 16:43:46 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/6qQnRSv62mg/nola-movingforward-villavaso.mp3" length="3787635" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">66216A26-D376-47AF-ADF2-6DBDA92276F8</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> New Orleans Moving Forward Stephen Villavso, FAICP, of Villavaso &amp; Associates, discusses the current planning status of New Orleans and the future of the city.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>2010 National Planning Conference</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>15:46</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Complete Streets: Best Policy &amp; Implementation Practices</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Complete Streets</p>

<p>Listen to a discussion on complete streets with Barbara McCann, Executive Director of The National Complete Streets Coalition, Sarah Zimmerman, Senior Staff Attorney for The National Policy and Legal Analysis Network to Prevent Childhood Obesity (NPLAN), and hosted by APA's Research Associate, David Morley.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 16:41:14 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/fKe2KTKSl-Q/completestreets.mp3" length="3976405" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F432B296-8EEF-45D8-9A5C-5F218C455D06</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Complete Streets Listen to a discussion on complete streets with Barbara McCann, Executive Director of The National Complete Streets Coalition, Sarah Zimmerman, Senior Staff Attorney for The National Policy and Legal Analysis Network to Prevent Childhood</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Complete Streets Listen to a discussion on complete streets with Barbara McCann, Executive Director of The National Complete Streets Coalition, Sarah Zimmerman, Senior Staff Attorney for The National Policy and Legal Analysis Network to Prevent Childhood Obesity (NPLAN), and hosted by APA's Research Associate, David Morley.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>16:34</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hazard Mitigration: Integrating Best Practices Into Planning</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Hazard Mitigation Planning</p>

<p>Is your community prepared if disaster strikes? John Wilson from Lee County, Florida, and Julia Burrows from Roseville, California, discuss how their respective communities created hazard mitigation plans. Roseville and Lee County are two featured case studies in the new Planning Advisory Service report, Hazard Mitigation: Integrating Best Practices into Planning (PAS 560).</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 16:39:30 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/IT3IBvKs9q8/hazardmitigation2010.mp3" length="5945320" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">323B4D6B-4E4D-4E93-AAE5-D5C9670F1ABC</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Hazard Mitigation Planning Is your community prepared if disaster strikes? John Wilson from Lee County, Florida, and Julia Burrows from Roseville, California, discuss how their respective communities created hazard mitigation plans. Roseville and Lee Cou</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Hazard Mitigation Planning Is your community prepared if disaster strikes? John Wilson from Lee County, Florida, and Julia Burrows from Roseville, California, discuss how their respective communities created hazard mitigation plans. Roseville and Lee County are two featured case studies in the new Planning Advisory Service report, Hazard Mitigation: Integrating Best Practices into Planning (PAS 560).</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>24:46</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Penny Wise, Pound Fuelish:New Measures of Housing + Transportation Affordability</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Penny Wise, Pound Fuelish:
<br />New Measures of Housing + Transportation Affordability
<br />July 20, 2010</p>

<p>Under the traditional definition of housing affordability, seven out of 10 U.S. communities are considered "affordable" to the typical household. But in almost all metro regions of the country, when the definition of affordability includes both housing and transportation costs, the number of communities affordable to households earning the area median income decreases significantly.</p>

<p>The Center for Neighborhood Technology (CNT) has developed the Housing+Transportation (H+T) Index to address this shortcoming. The index is a publicly available database that demonstrates the transportation costs associated with a home's location thereby providing a more accurate measure of a community's affordability.</p>

<p>Peter Haas from CNT provided an overview of the H+T Index, key findings, its public policy applications, and reported on related federal policy initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 16:36:21 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/GcUj9rXh_ws/tuesapa-cnt.mp3" length="15655855" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5315EBB2-D6D8-4703-B12F-0BE9A7C72D2A</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Penny Wise, Pound Fuelish: New Measures of Housing + Transportation Affordability July 20, 2010 Under the traditional definition of housing affordability, seven out of 10 U.S. communities are considered "affordable" to the typical household. But in almos</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:05:13</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: More Smiles, Less Miles</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>More Smiles, Less Miles
<br />May 11, 2010</p>

<p>Transportation is a major consideration when planning a region, city, suburb, or even a town center. It has become increasingly common for plans to discuss greenhouse gas emissions in addition to traffic congestion. The good news is that every day, more people are riding clean, riding less, and riding together. This means that millions are spending less on gasoline, helping our country become energy secure, and reducing emissions.</p>

<p>John Addison, author of the book Save Gas, Save the Planet, discussed how planners, government leaders, and engaged citizens can help create vibrant and sustainable communities through rail, bus rapid transit, last miles solutions to make transit accessible, bicycle and walking mode shifts, electric and high mileage cars, transportation demand management programs, and smart growth initiatives that include transit oriented development.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 16:34:35 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/FZj76-cygek/tuesapa-moresmileslessmiles.mp3" length="68639046" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C2D2A7BE-0A73-4947-BFAB-6CDE046320D2</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> More Smiles, Less Miles May 11, 2010 Transportation is a major consideration when planning a region, city, suburb, or even a town center. It has become increasingly common for plans to discuss greenhouse gas emissions in addition to traffic congestion. T</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:11:29</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Planning for a New Energy and Climate Future</title>
            <description><![CDATA[This podcast features Scott Shuford, AICP, Planning and Development Director of Onslow County, North Carolina, Suzanne Rynne, AICP, Manager of APA's Green Communities Research Center, and Jan Mueller, Senior Policy Associate with the Environmental and Energy Study Institute, the three coauthors of PAS report 558, Planning for a New Energy and Climate Future. Listen as they discuss the various regional effects of climate change, different approaches to mitigation and adaptation, and how different communities are reducing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions while exploring ways to increase renewable energy opportunities.]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 16:33:25 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/s5gfmLkKd5U/newenergyclimatefuture.mp3" length="8615209" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4736EC17-58CD-47C6-B990-112A2E841E07</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>This podcast features Scott Shuford, AICP, Planning and Development Director of Onslow County, North Carolina, Suzanne Rynne, AICP, Manager of APA's Green Communities Research Center, and Jan Mueller, Senior Policy Associate with the Environmental and Ene</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>This podcast features Scott Shuford, AICP, Planning and Development Director of Onslow County, North Carolina, Suzanne Rynne, AICP, Manager of APA's Green Communities Research Center, and Jan Mueller, Senior Policy Associate with the Environmental and Energy Study Institute, the three coauthors of PAS report 558, Planning for a New Energy and Climate Future. Listen as they discuss the various regional effects of climate change, different approaches to mitigation and adaptation, and how different communities are reducing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions while exploring ways to increase renewable energy opportunities.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>35:53</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Chicago's Central Area Action Plan</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Chicago's Central Area Action Plan
<br />April 20, 2010</p>

<p>Over the past decade, the central six square miles of Chicago have undergone a dramatic transformation with unprecedented growth in both the residential and educational sectors as well as the construction of new public facilities and museums (most notably the opening of Millennium Park and the modern wing of the Art Institute on the north side of Grant Park).</p>

<p>The 2003 Central Area Plan provided a broad framework for new infrastructure and open space projects as well as a basis for Zoning Reform in 2004, and the 2009 Central Area Action Plan builds on this framework. The public projects are prioritized and quantified and growth projections updated to reflect current market conditions.</p>

<p>The CAAP takes as a given that the majority of new construction will be by the private sector, but that key public improvements will facilitate this investment and improve the quality of life for everyone who lives, works, or plays in the core of this world city.</p>

<p>Benet Haller from the City of Chicago presented this plan and discussed the impact of the global economy and other factors on the final recommendations.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 16:31:52 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/VXubfDy4INo/tuesapa-chicagocentralareaactionplan.mp3" length="58079318" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">C15FB901-43D0-49E6-ACB4-97DFA7A927EA</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Chicago's Central Area Action Plan April 20, 2010 Over the past decade, the central six square miles of Chicago have undergone a dramatic transformation with unprecedented growth in both the residential and educational sectors as well as the construction</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:00:29</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[2010 National Planning Conference] "Clear As Mud": Planning for the Rebuilding of New Orleans</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Clear As Mud</p>

<p>Hear authors Rob Olshansky and Laurie Johnson discuss their new release Clear As Mud: Planning for the Rebuilding of New Orleans. Olshansky and Johnson discuss how Hurricane Katrina differed from other international disasters and their experience in tracking the rebuilding of New Orleans.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 16:28:27 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/sA6irxsKrSY/clearasmud.mp3" length="6281415" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2C99CDE9-D603-4FA1-9835-C847B7DF81E1</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Clear As Mud Hear authors Rob Olshansky and Laurie Johnson discuss their new release Clear As Mud: Planning for the Rebuilding of New Orleans. Olshansky and Johnson discuss how Hurricane Katrina differed from other international disasters and their exper</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>2010 National Planning Conference</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>26:10</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: The Evolution of Our Suburbs</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Evolution of Our Suburbs
<br />March 16, 2010</p>

<p>For the last few decades the Chicago region has been suburbanizing with little regard to energy use, climate change, and urban form. The relentless pursuit of property tax revenue and a focus on single uses and single-site developments distracts many suburban communities from the task of planning for a sustainable and livable built environment.</p>

<p>As planners, what should be our approach to the future of our suburbs? Can we afford to continue the growth and development patterns of the past few decades? Are there new growth patterns and new development tools that we can get ready now to be prepared for a different future?</p>

<p>Mahender Vasandani from M Square Urban Design shared thoughts on these and other questions in an effort to start a dialogue among planners about where we go from here and how.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 16:26:22 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/wYXzYEAK3Vk/tuesapa-suburbanevolution.mp3" length="14713435" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0379951A-AA5F-460D-BE98-D3836EC2BB61</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> The Evolution of Our Suburbs March 16, 2010 For the last few decades the Chicago region has been suburbanizing with little regard to energy use, climate change, and urban form. The relentless pursuit of property tax revenue and a focus on single uses and</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:01:18</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[2010 National Planning Conference] Food and Planning in New Orleans</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Food and Planning in New Orleans</p>

<p>Among the many things New Orleans is famous for is its food. Increasingly, that food is locally grown. Vanessa Ulmer, the Policy and Advocacy Coordinator with the Prevention Research Center at Tulane University, joined Broadcast APA to talk about local food, fighting obesity, and citywide polices that increase food access. She also gives listeners tips on where to eat in New Orleans — all of which are included in the New Orleans Food System Guide, compiled by APA's Planning & Community Health Research Center.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 16:25:07 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/UUGqy4EHfCs/foodplanning-nola.mp3" length="2798317" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2990A188-81EE-4592-9D14-CB9C5EEED0B5</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Food and Planning in New Orleans Among the many things New Orleans is famous for is its food. Increasingly, that food is locally grown. Vanessa Ulmer, the Policy and Advocacy Coordinator with the Prevention Research Center at Tulane University, joined Br</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>2010 National Planning Conference</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>11:39</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hazard Mitigation in New Zealand: A presentation by Kristin Hoskin</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Visiting Fellowship in New Zealand</p>

<p>In 2008, Center Manager Jim Schwab, AICP, was invited by the Centre for Advanced Engineering in New Zealand (CAENZ), located at the University of Canterbury in Christchurch, to serve as a Visiting Fellow, studying New Zealand hazards planning and offering consultation on national hazards policy. Schwab's trip lasted three weeks from July 25 to August 15, 2008, during which time he traveled the country, delivering seven different lectures and seminars, including presentation at the Australasian Natural Hazards Conference and to a joint meeting of staff members of the Ministry of the Environment and the Ministry of Civil Defense and Emergency Management.</p>

<p>A year later, in October 2009, Kristin Hoskin, who had managed Jim's itinerary for CAENZ, visited APA in Chicago, where she delivered a presentation and was interviewed for a podcast.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 16:12:11 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/DK16viWlZfw/hoskinnz-presentation.mp3" length="12929710" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DDB8F6F1-4F05-4F3D-A1AA-3ACFE1EA544B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Visiting Fellowship in New Zealand In 2008, Center Manager Jim Schwab, AICP, was invited by the Centre for Advanced Engineering in New Zealand (CAENZ), located at the University of Canterbury in Christchurch, to serve as a Visiting Fellow, studying New Z</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Visiting Fellowship in New Zealand In 2008, Center Manager Jim Schwab, AICP, was invited by the Centre for Advanced Engineering in New Zealand (CAENZ), located at the University of Canterbury in Christchurch, to serve as a Visiting Fellow, studying New Zealand hazards planning and offering consultation on national hazards policy. Schwab's trip lasted three weeks from July 25 to August 15, 2008, during which time he traveled the country, delivering seven different lectures and seminars, including presentation at the Australasian Natural Hazards Conference and to a joint meeting of staff members of the Ministry of the Environment and the Ministry of Civil Defense and Emergency Management. A year later, in October 2009, Kristin Hoskin, who had managed Jim's itinerary for CAENZ, visited APA in Chicago, where she delivered a presentation and was interviewed for a podcast.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>53:52</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Quarterly Legislative &amp; Policy Briefing (February 22nd, 2010)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Updates on government planning policy]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 16:09:57 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Gr6TvqMnSkg/legislativebriefing-feb2010.mp3" length="24234978" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">023CB56D-C8A3-4F9C-A67D-1888EB4C2ABF</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle>Updates on government planning policy</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Updates on government planning policy</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>57:42</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[2010 National Planning Conference] Post-Katrina Demographics (with Rafe Rabalais)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Post-Katrina Demographics</p>

<p>Estimating the population of New Orleans was a tricky business in the months — and years — after Hurricane Katrina. With the 2010 Census coming up, planner Rafe Rabalais talks about what the official decennial count means for the city, shifts in local demographics since the August 2005 storm, and the tool his company developed to track the resettlement of New Orleans.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 16:04:51 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/900e9sOjsuk/postkatrinademographics.mp3" length="4674795" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8BD5EB24-A4EB-4859-8C5E-239405047ED7</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Post-Katrina Demographics Estimating the population of New Orleans was a tricky business in the months — and years — after Hurricane Katrina. With the 2010 Census coming up, planner Rafe Rabalais talks about what the official decennial count means for th</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>2010 National Planning Conference</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>19:28</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Foreclosing the Dream (Media Briefing)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>New Book Sounds Death Knell for Suburbs
<br />Media Briefing Presentation</p>

<p>CHICAGO — The suburbs are in a fragile state and it is only going to get worse. The recent foreclosure crisis has masked the true, underlying problems facing U.S. suburbs. These are basic structural problems that will not vanish with a global economic recovery.</p>

<p>Foreclosing the Dream: How America's Housing Crisis Is Reshaping Our Cities and Suburbs, published by the American Planning Association (APA), is the first book to look beyond financial manipulations to understand what truly fueled the foreclosure crisis and what it means for the future of suburbs and cities.</p>

<p>According to the book:</p>

<p>Higher rates of foreclosures in new suburbs and exurbs compared to lower rates in cities show that the American Dream is changing.
<br />The number of households in the 30 to 45 age group has declined by 3.4 million since 2000 and this has reduced demand for large suburban houses.
<br />The stereotypical "white flight exodus" from central cities has been reversed in most large metropolitan areas.
<br />Changing demographics and consumer attitudes coupled with political support for compact development, transit investments, and awareness about climate change all point to a dramatic shift in development patterns.</p>

<p>Author William H. Lucy, AICP, is an urban planning professor at the University of Virginia. He is the first to examine the full impact of foreclosures in conjunction with other factors such as the influence of politics, household demographic changes, household income, and national housing policies to generate a comprehensive view of what is happening in our communities.</p>

<p>In examining the foreclosure rates in 236 counties in the 35 largest metropolitan areas, combined with housing and income characteristics in each of the 50 states, Lucy provides a more complete understanding of the housing and financial crisis that began in 2008. Lucy's research shows that central city improvements throughout the past decade illustrate a pattern of growing revival.</p>

<p>"These shifts will lead to shorter commutes to work and less carbon dioxide emissions," Lucy said. "But these same shifts will lead to more poverty in suburbs and more financially stressed suburban governments."</p>

<p>The ongoing deterioration of the suburbs was actually masked by the housing price run-up that occurred between 2002 and 2006. And the foreclosure crisis has only served to accelerate the suburban deterioration.</p>

<p>"Two key questions will be answered during the next decade," Lucy said. "Is 2010 the threshold for rapid city revival in coming decades just as 1950 was the threshold for rapid suburban development during the next half century? And will developers, lenders, and government officials facilitate these positive changes in housing markets while also adapting to support declining suburbs?"</p>

<p>"Foreclosing the Dream is a warning for communities and elected officials. Lucy identifies a fundamental change in our communities that will only continue to gain momentum. His research illustrates that the foreclosure crisis has greater implications beyond just revising our current lending practices," said W. Paul Farmer, FAICP, APA's Chief Executive Officer.</p>

<p>The book includes specific data for the following 35 metropolitan areas: Atlanta; Baltimore; Boston; Buffalo; Charlotte; Chicago; Cincinnati; Cleveland; Columbus; Dallas; Denver; Detroit; Houston; Indianapolis; Kansas City; Las Vegas; Los Angeles; Miami; Milwaukee; Minneapolis/St. Paul; New York; Orlando; Philadelphia; Phoenix; Pittsburgh; Portland, OR; Sacramento; San Antonio; San Diego; San Francisco; Seattle; St. Louis; Tampa/St. Petersburg; Virginia Beach; Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Foreclosing the Dream is available through APAPlanningBooks.com for $52.95 ($34.95 for APA members). ISBN: 978-1-932364-78-1. Paperback: 208 pp.</p>

<p>Lucy is the Lawrence Lewis Jr. Professor of Urban and Environmental Planning at the University of Virginia. Foreclosing the Dream is the first book to examine the broader context of the foreclosure crisis in terms of causes and effects, including influences of household demographic changes, household income, national housing policies, and national politics on the changing prospects of cities and suburbs throughout the United States. Lucy also is the author, with David Phillips, of Tomorrow's Cities Tomorrow's Suburbs, which was published by the American Planning Association in 2006.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/K6xgk9rqM7M/foreclosingthedream_mediabriefing.mp3" length="11216635" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E757E2A6-E1D8-496A-9AAD-0B6AC6A09B12</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> New Book Sounds Death Knell for Suburbs Media Briefing Presentation CHICAGO — The suburbs are in a fragile state and it is only going to get worse. The recent foreclosure crisis has masked the true, underlying problems facing U.S. suburbs. These are basi</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> New Book Sounds Death Knell for Suburbs Media Briefing Presentation CHICAGO — The suburbs are in a fragile state and it is only going to get worse. The recent foreclosure crisis has masked the true, underlying problems facing U.S. suburbs. These are basic structural problems that will not vanish with a global economic recovery. Foreclosing the Dream: How America's Housing Crisis Is Reshaping Our Cities and Suburbs, published by the American Planning Association (APA), is the first book to look beyond financial manipulations to understand what truly fueled the foreclosure crisis and what it means for the future of suburbs and cities. According to the book: Higher rates of foreclosures in new suburbs and exurbs compared to lower rates in cities show that the American Dream is changing. The number of households in the 30 to 45 age group has declined by 3.4 million since 2000 and this has reduced demand for large suburban houses. The stereotypical "white flight exodus" from central cities has been reversed in most large metropolitan areas. Changing demographics and consumer attitudes coupled with political support for compact development, transit investments, and awareness about climate change all point to a dramatic shift in development patterns. Author William H. Lucy, AICP, is an urban planning professor at the University of Virginia. He is the first to examine the full impact of foreclosures in conjunction with other factors such as the influence of politics, household demographic changes, household income, and national housing policies to generate a comprehensive view of what is happening in our communities. In examining the foreclosure rates in 236 counties in the 35 largest metropolitan areas, combined with housing and income characteristics in each of the 50 states, Lucy provides a more complete understanding of the housing and financial crisis that began in 2008. Lucy's research shows that central city improvements throughout the past decade illustrate a pattern of growing revival. "These shifts will lead to shorter commutes to work and less carbon dioxide emissions," Lucy said. "But these same shifts will lead to more poverty in suburbs and more financially stressed suburban governments." The ongoing deterioration of the suburbs was actually masked by the housing price run-up that occurred between 2002 and 2006. And the foreclosure crisis has only served to accelerate the suburban deterioration. "Two key questions will be answered during the next decade," Lucy said. "Is 2010 the threshold for rapid city revival in coming decades just as 1950 was the threshold for rapid suburban development during the next half century? And will developers, lenders, and government officials facilitate these positive changes in housing markets while also adapting to support declining suburbs?" "Foreclosing the Dream is a warning for communities and elected officials. Lucy identifies a fundamental change in our communities that will only continue to gain momentum. His research illustrates that the foreclosure crisis has greater implications beyond just revising our current lending practices," said W. Paul Farmer, FAICP, APA's Chief Executive Officer. The book includes specific data for the following 35 metropolitan areas: Atlanta; Baltimore; Boston; Buffalo; Charlotte; Chicago; Cincinnati; Cleveland; Columbus; Dallas; Denver; Detroit; Houston; Indianapolis; Kansas City; Las Vegas; Los Angeles; Miami; Milwaukee; Minneapolis/St. Paul; New York; Orlando; Philadelphia; Phoenix; Pittsburgh; Portland, OR; Sacramento; San Antonio; San Diego; San Francisco; Seattle; St. Louis; Tampa/St. Petersburg; Virginia Beach; Washington, D.C. Foreclosing the Dream is available through APAPlanningBooks.com for $52.95 ($34.95 for APA members). ISBN: 978-1-932364-78-1. Paperback: 208 pp. Lucy is the Lawrence Lewis Jr. Professor of Urban and Environmental Planning at the University of Virginia. Foreclosing the Dream is the first book to examine the broader contex</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>26:42</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Beyond Burnham</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Beyond Burnham
<br />February 23, 2010</p>

<p>Since the publication of Burnham and Bennett's Plan of Chicago in 1909, powerful institutions such as the Chicago Plan Commission and Regional Transportation Authority, among others, have emerged to promote metropolitan goals in the Chicago region. In their new illustrated book on the topic, Joseph Schwieterman and Alan Mammoser show how the human face of planning appears in the interplay between public officials and citizen advocates.</p>

<p>Schwieterman and Mammoser shared how a century of visionary planning for metropolitan Chicago has shaped the region's identity and character. From Daniel H. Burnham and Edward H. Bennett's famed 1909 Plan of Chicago to the push for superhighways and airports to battles over urban sprawl, they described the big personalities and the "big plans" they espoused.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/bhiId3Mdu6E/tuesapa-beyondburnham.mp3" length="14955315" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EB71ED20-39AA-4EF0-8D54-9FFCAF739E12</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Beyond Burnham February 23, 2010 Since the publication of Burnham and Bennett's Plan of Chicago in 1909, powerful institutions such as the Chicago Plan Commission and Regional Transportation Authority, among others, have emerged to promote metropolitan g</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>1:02:18</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tuesdays at APA: Data Mining on Federal Websites</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Data Mining on Federal Websites
<br />January 26, 2010</p>

<p>Since the late 1990s, planners have grown to rely on the rapid exchange of information and enhanced data analysis tools enabled by sophisticated computing power. With this proliferation of information and technology, planners need practical strategies for making sense of electronic information.</p>

<p>John Shuler, from the University of Illinois at Chicago, and Rana Salzmann, from APA, discussed how to use the Web to find relevant planning information efficiently and commented on how the Internet's reach has changed the practice of planning through the expansion of digital government services.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 15:49:25 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/1Vt3y3kun64/tuesapa-datamining.mp3" length="12513405" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">93A90405-074C-4DAE-9BA3-E5905277C6FC</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Data Mining on Federal Websites January 26, 2010 Since the late 1990s, planners have grown to rely on the rapid exchange of information and enhanced data analysis tools enabled by sophisticated computing power. With this proliferation of information and </itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Tuesdays at APA</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>52:08</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Conservation (Timothy Beatley and Patrice Frey)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Green Community Conservation</p>

<p>In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors Timothy Beatley and Patrice Frey.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 15:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/xFmahCNdJ9g/gc-beatley-frey.mp3" length="3170476" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9AD63AD9-2DE7-4F6C-93EC-22D165CA520E</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Green Community Conservation In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors Timothy Beatley and Patrice Frey.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Green Community Podcast Series

The health of our planet and our selves depends on how we plan, design, and construct the world between our buildings. Hear from contributors of Green Community, the new book from APA published in conjunction with the National Building Museum.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>13:10</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Density and Transportation (with F. Kaid Benfield, Fred Hansen, and Mariela Alfonzo)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Green Community Density and Transportation</p>

<p>In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors F. Kaid Benfield, Fred Hansen, and Mariela Alfonzo.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 15:42:29 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/g7PQsRUwk3E/gc-benfield-hansen-alfonzo.mp3" length="5633619" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">17D2C808-F43D-4484-8779-D920E36218D8</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Green Community Density and Transportation In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors F. Kaid Benfield, Fred Hansen, and Mariela Alfonzo.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Green Community Podcast Series

The health of our planet and our selves depends on how we plan, design, and construct the world between our buildings. Hear from contributors of Green Community, the new book from APA published in conjunction with the National Building Museum.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>23:25</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Health (with Carolyn Steel)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Local and Global Health</p>

<p>Featuring: Carolyn Steel and Esther M. Sternberg</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 15:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/EeZSV32viaw/gc-carolynsteel.mp3" length="4912123" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D6F14F7E-C2DD-4E6E-B698-8DFEDD48B980</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Local and Global Health Featuring: Carolyn Steel and Esther M. Sternberg</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary> Local and Global Health Featuring: Carolyn Steel and Esther M. Sternberg</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>20:25</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Energy (with Erica and Mark Heller)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Green Community Energy (Part II)</p>

<p>In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors Erica Heller, AICP, and Mark Heller, AICP.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 15:36:02 -0600</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/cY11uabpMnY/gc-palladino-hellers.mp3" length="6640257" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">80847845-2E75-4050-AE76-EB60F707D6DD</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Green Community Energy (Part II) In this episode, listen to Green Community contributors Erica Heller, AICP, and Mark Heller, AICP.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Green Community Podcast Series

The health of our planet and our selves depends on how we plan, design, and construct the world between our buildings. Hear from contributors of Green Community, the new book from APA published in conjunction with the National Building Museum.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>27:40</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Introduction (with Susan Piedmont Palladino and Timothy Mennel)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Green Community Introduction</p>

<p>In this episode, listen to Green Community co-editors Timothy Mennel and Susan Piedmont-Palladino discuss contributor insights and the book's production</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 15:35:23 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/o2hHSQGt6_8/gc-susanpalladino.mp3" length="5378430" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53E115D3-F422-4A7C-AA90-5D6BBB6A989B</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Green Community Introduction In this episode, listen to Green Community co-editors Timothy Mennel and Susan Piedmont-Palladino discuss contributor insights and the book's production</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Green Community Podcast Series

The health of our planet and our selves depends on how we plan, design, and construct the world between our buildings. Hear from contributors of Green Community, the new book from APA published in conjunction with the National Building Museum.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>22:22</itunes:duration>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Green Community: Energy (with Mary Pelletier)</title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Green Community Energy</p>

<p>In this episode, listen to Green Community contributor Mary Rickel Pelletier.</p>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 15:35:45 -0500</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AmericanPlanningAssociation/~5/Xb3qbmv-0pU/gc-marypelletier.mp3" length="5372361" type="audio/mpeg"/>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DBC92DE1-61A4-4720-9464-797499B001D1</guid>
            <itunes:author>American Planning Association</itunes:author>
            <itunes:subtitle> Green Community Energy In this episode, listen to Green Community contributor Mary Rickel Pelletier.</itunes:subtitle>
            <itunes:summary>Green Community Podcast Series

The health of our planet and our selves depends on how we plan, design, and construct the world between our buildings. Hear from contributors of Green Community, the new book from APA published in conjunction with the National Building Museum.</itunes:summary>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
            <itunes:duration>22:20</itunes:duration>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
